<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/</link><description>Recent content on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:17:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS CodeCommit</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2017/01/09/aws-codecommit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:17:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2017/01/09/aws-codecommit/</guid><description>The Picture So Far I’ve used a number of VCS flavors and platforms over the years. I started with CVS, moved on to SVN for a good long while, and was finally converted over to Git long after it had achieved its critical mass. I had a sourceforge account (which I loved) long before it became the reviled product it is today, flirted for a bit with beanstalk, and now use github in its public and private forms on a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Pressing Matters</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2015/08/10/pressing-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 06:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2015/08/10/pressing-matters/</guid><description>WordPress to Octopress and Back Again This site is once again running on WordPress. It’s been through many changes since its earliest incarnation as handwritten static HTML. There have been versions based on custom PHP frameworks, a pyblosxom-based variant, and most recently, the Octopress installation. Directly prior to Octopress, the site had already been using WordPress. So why did I leave and why did I come back?
What I don’t like about WordPress Its relative ease of installation and use for newcomers belies the big cumbersome application that WordPress really is underneath.</description></item><item><title>Vent Hood Build</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/09/vent-hood-build/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 17:40:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/09/vent-hood-build/</guid><description>When I originally built the electric brewery, it was located at the back of the garage in front of a window. During boils I would open the window and point a small fan from above the kettle to move steam outside. In our new house, the brewery got moved out of the garage and into its own space in the basement. This meant I would need a new ventilation system.</description></item><item><title>Holiday Poster Boards</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/07/holiday-poster-boards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 19:18:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/07/holiday-poster-boards/</guid><description>A while back [ok – headed toward 2 years ago now – I’m way behind on blog posts], Creative Market held a Christmas party, giving its employees and community members an opportunity to hang out and interact. As the Creative Market brewer-in-residence, I was asked to provide some beer for the event. This would be a general audience event and not a room full of seasoned homebrew beer geeks like I was more accustomed to.</description></item><item><title>Itinerant Brewing Labels</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/bottle-labels/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 16:37:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/bottle-labels/</guid><description>This is a collection of beer bottle labels that I designed for a few of my homebrews.
||| ||| |||</description></item><item><title>Brew Log</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/brew-log/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 16:24:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/brew-log/</guid><description>This is an index to keep track of everything I’ve brewed along with the brew date, batch number, and link to the write up.
Kalakalaky IPA – 05/2009 Blonde Bombshell – 07/08/09 Great Lakes Edmund Fitzgerald Porter – 11/15/09 – Clone #1 Bell’s Two Hearted Ale – 02/15/10 – Clone #2 – Keg #1 Scottish Zombie Jesus – 04/04/10 – All Grain #1 El Jefe – 05/02/10 Oaked Arrogant Bastard – 08/08/10 – Clone #3 Shambler Amber – 11/06/10 11-11-11 Gun Stock Ale – 11/26/10 Razzmatazz – 01/13/11 – Mead #1 The Commoner – 02/05/11 – All Grain #6 Shill For Hire – 02/13/11 SMaSH – 03/12/11 The Belgian – 03/27/11 The Mayan – 04/10/11 Cherry Wheat – 05/14/11 The Redhead – 06/26/11 The Commoner (v2) – 08/06/11 The Shill (v2) – 10/02/11 Nectarine Soda – 10/07/11 Pumpkin Ale – 10/23/11 Strawberry Balsamic Basil Soda – 10/30/11 Sour Pear Saison – 11/25/11 The Farmhouse (Dark Saison) – 01/07/12 Folie a Deux (Kriek) – 02/03/12 Die Gose – 03/09/12 Kolsch – 03/21/12 Black Briar Melomel (Blackberry Mead) – 03/24/12 The Greyhound (Grapefruit Pale Ale) – 04/21/12 Uruk-Hai (Bohemian Pilsner) – 05/04/12 Apricot Melomel – 06/11/12 Boxcar Betty (Belgian IPA) – 06/13/12 Flanders de l’Arménie (Flanders Red w/ Apricot) – 06/22/12 Corvus (Fig Saison) – 07/04/12 Kahve Fali (Turkish Coffee Stout) – 07/20/12 100% Brett Trois IPA – 08/24/12 das Orakel (Berliner Weisse) – 09/11/12 (Dumped) Altbier – 09/24/12 The Highlander (Strong Scotch Ale) – 10/13/12 Stoopid Flanders (Flanders Red) – 11/05/12 Tooth + Claw (ESB) – 11/14/12 Brewlab Dubbel – 11/18/12 das Orakel v2 – 11/24/12 (Dumped) Ouachita Black (Balcones Barrel Aged Imperial Stout) – 12/28/12 Ruby Redhead (Irish Red Ale w/ Blackberries) – 02/02/13 Brewlab Barrel Trippel – 02/24/13 Brown Ale – 03/06/1 Flanders #3 – 03/27/13 Saison Trois – 04/16/13 Freighthopper – 06/05/13 Quadrapendence – 07/04/13 Citron Saison – 08/10/13 Shambler Amber V2 – 10/17/13 Kahve Fali – 11/10/13 Greyhound Apollo IPA – 02/01/14 (dumped) Apollo R2 – 02/17/14 American Farmhouse ’14 – 04/26/14 The Doorkeeper – 07/27/14</description></item><item><title>Electric Brewery Upgrade – Part 1</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/2013/05/15/electric-brewery-upgrade-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/2013/05/15/electric-brewery-upgrade-part-1/</guid><description>It’s closing in on two years now since the last blog update. Even though I haven’t been keeping content updated, I’ve still been busy brewing. Maybe a future post will spend a bit more time reflecting on all of those brews. That is not this post. This post is all about the new pilot brewing system I built over the past winter.
Incremental Updates I’ve been brewing on essentially the same propane system for the past several years with just a few minor tweaks here and there.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Fermentation Controller – Part 3</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/05/14/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/05/14/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-3/</guid><description>Part 1 and part 2 covered getting the Raspberry Pi booted up and configured with a basic software stack for developing on top of. With that out of the way, we can focus on wiring up the remaining hardware components. There will be two types of IO devices wired to the Pi – temperature sensors and SSR’s.
Temperature Sensors The temperature sensors being used are small digital thermometers which communicate using the Dallas 1-wire network protocol.</description></item><item><title>Product Review: Taylor Digital Thermometer</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/product-review-taylor-digital-thermometer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 23:26:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/product-review-taylor-digital-thermometer/</guid><description>Pros Price: It can typically be found on sale online for $16-$20.
Temperature Alarm: This works great in the HLT to know when strike or sparge water has reached its target temperature. It can also be used in the boil kettle to notify you when the wort is approaching a boiling point and the most susceptible to boil overs.
Timer: Use this to keep track of when the mash and boil are done.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Fermentation Controller – Part 2</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/24/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/24/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-2/</guid><description>In part 1 I walked through getting the Raspberry Pi initially up and running. Once you’re logged in, you can immediately start hooking up sensors and start polling them directly from the command line. However, you’re likely going to want some more software installed for additional tasks. For my fermentation controller, I’ve decided on the following software stack.
Software Stack Graphite StatsD Node.js MongoDB All of the data read from sensors along with GPIO state changes will all be recorded in Graphite.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Fermentation Controller – Part 1</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/20/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/20/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-1/</guid><description>The Raspberry Pi is a cheap single-board computer with generic IO features which make it ideal for brewery automation projects. The BrewPi project is just one example. I decided to assemble a similar project with the goal of being able to monitor, log, and control the fermentation temperature of two 5-6 gallon carboys of fermenting beer.
Parts List Raspberry Pi SD Card WiFi Adapter SD Card Reader Micro USB Power Adapter Network cable Bootstrapping The Raspberry Pi board by itself isn’t actually enough to do anything with.</description></item><item><title>Quick Tips for Optimizing Your Brew Day</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/quick-tips-for-optimizing-your-brew-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 20:10:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/quick-tips-for-optimizing-your-brew-day/</guid><description>The average all grain brew day generally takes between 4 and 6 hours from beginning to end. Some of the steps have a fixed duration. A 60 minute boil will never take any less time than an hour to complete. There’s no way around that fact. However, there are other areas with the potential to optimize and speed up the brew day.
When you optimize your own brew day look for ways not only to shorten the overall time spent brewing, but also to extract the most value from that time.</description></item><item><title>Keeping it Clean</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/keeping-it-clean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 22:12:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/keeping-it-clean/</guid><description>Cleaning &amp;amp; sanitization Most of the time involved in beer making is a hands off process as the yeast does its work. A comparatively small portion of time is actively spent on preparing the yeast, wort and, later on, packaging the resulting beer. A good deal of any brewer’s hands on time is dedicated to cleaning and sanitizing tasks. So what is the difference between the two processes and when is each appropriate?</description></item><item><title>10 Essential Brew Day Terms Defined</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/10-essential-brew-day-terms-defined/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/10-essential-brew-day-terms-defined/</guid><description>Newcomers to the homebrewing world will quickly encounter a vast landscape of unfamiliar acronyms and bizarre terminology. When you’re still trying to learn the basic brewing processes, finding your way through the slew of unusual jargon adds its own steep learning curve. Here are a few of the most common terms along with their definitions to help ease the way.
LHBS – Local Home Brew Store The LHBS is the place where your brew days will often begin.</description></item><item><title>Five Tips For a Successful Brew Day</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/five-tips-for-a-successful-brew-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 06:22:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/five-tips-for-a-successful-brew-day/</guid><description>1 – Hot Break Achieving a good rolling boil is an important step in the beer making process for several reasons. First, boiling sterilizes the beer, killing any unwanted bacteria that might be hanging around just waiting to spoil your hard work. Boil off reduces the overall volume, concentrating it. Without boiling, you’d end up with a beer that probably tasted water down. Boiling also causes caramelization, contributing additional flavor to the beer.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Extract Brewing Methods</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/beyond-extract-brewing-methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 23:53:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/beyond-extract-brewing-methods/</guid><description>There is no question that award winning beers can be made using malt extract as the the basis of their recipe. However, when using extracts, much of the work in converting the grain’s starches into usable sugars has already been done for the brewer. This also means that much of the control over the end product is in the hands of the extract producers and not the brewer. By using all grain and leaving malt extracts behind, brewers can take more control over the flavor profiles of the beers they are creating.</description></item><item><title>Extract Brewing Methods</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/extract-brewing-methods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 01:23:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/extract-brewing-methods/</guid><description>There may be almost as many ways to make beer as there are different styles of beer. While the basic formula is to combine a hoppy sugary liquid with yeast to ultimately produce a fermented beverage, the steps to get there can vary greatly. These different approaches also tend to affect brewing process, equipment and the ingredients that are required.
Hopped Kits At the simplest end of the spectrum are pre-hopped extract kits.</description></item><item><title>Thermometers</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/thermometers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 06:16:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/thermometers/</guid><description>One of the most common useful pieces of equipment in the home brewery is the thermometer. Measuring, monitoring and ultimately, controlling temperature is a key aspect of producing quality beer. It starts with making sure that the water is being heated to the correct temperature for mashing and later on for sparging. It continues with getting the boiled wort cooled down to an appropriate temperature to pitch the yeast. After fermentation and carbonation, the beer needs to be cooled down to the correct serving temperature.</description></item><item><title>A Beer Style Primer</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/introduction-styles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 06:40:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/introduction-styles/</guid><description>Beers are typically categorized by their style. Styles are primarily defined by characteristics such as color, bitterness, alcohol content, ingredients, aroma, body, mouthfeel and flavor. They also often carry particular historical and regional significance. For instance, the Berliner Weisse began as a regional specialty style of Berlin while Munich Helles was first created in Munich.
While beers have probably been categorized into different styles based on their differing properties for as long as they have been brewed, it is possibly the acclaimed English beer writer Michael Jackson who pioneered modern beer style definitions with his 1977 book “The World Guide To Beer”.</description></item><item><title>Full Steam Ahead</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/19/full-steam-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/19/full-steam-ahead/</guid><description>I made my first steam beer about six months ago. It was my first brew of the year (not counting mead) and my first attempt at coming up with my own recipe. While there were a number of milestones that came with that brew, I wasn’t all that thrilled with the resulting beer. It wasn’t bad, but try as I might, I just could never find anything particularly noteworthy about it.</description></item><item><title>The Mayan</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/15/the-mayan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/15/the-mayan/</guid><description>The brewing process for me often starts with a simple concept or core thematic element. It could be an ingredient, a style, or some other idea serving as the inspiration for the beer. In this case a recent thread in the HBT forums brought up the idea of an end of the world brew.
According to some interpretations of the Mayan calendar the world is set to end on December, 23rd 2012.</description></item><item><title>The Belgian</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/07/31/the-belgian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/07/31/the-belgian/</guid><description>It’s been over a year since I’ve brewed something falling into the Belgian style category.
My last attempt was a golden strong ale called Blonde Bombshell.
It was also my second brewing experience ever. In the intervening time my knowledge and process has changed significantly.
I’ve gone from brewing partial-boil extract recipes taken from the internet to all-grain full-boil batches created from my own custom designed recipes. Regardless my advances, I’m always finding areas of my techniques and processes to improve upon from one session to the next.</description></item><item><title>Cherry Wheat</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/20/cherry-wheat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/20/cherry-wheat/</guid><description>As I’ve slowly worked my way through various new styles and ingredients to experiment with, fruit has long been on my list. I’ve been looking forward to making a beer featuring cherries for nearly a year now. The idea first came to me after seeing fresh ripe cherries at a local farmers market one weekend. Unfortunately, it was already late in the season and by the time I was finally ready the opportunity for market fresh cherries had passed.</description></item><item><title>Shilling Parti-gyle</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/17/shilling-parti-gyle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/17/shilling-parti-gyle/</guid><description>Batch #12 – All Grain #7
One of my favorite batches to date has been my Strong Scotch Ale all-grain recipe. One of the signature characteristics of most Scottish ales is a deep, rich malt profile. The flavors often a result of early century procedures producing kettle-scortched wort, modern day recreations are created from the caramelized reduction of the first runnings which is added back in with the rest of the wort at the end of the boil.</description></item><item><title>Monterey Getaway</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2011/02/24/monterey-getaway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2011/02/24/monterey-getaway/</guid><description>While recently assembling the brew log page, I realized that I haven’t written about anything other than brewing beer in quite a while. When I initially started writing I had four primary concepts in mind – a blend of food, beer, travel, and photography. Over time it seems some of these have fallen by the wayside in favor of my brewing posts. So, this post is a bit of catch up for the non-brewing category.</description></item><item><title>The Commoner</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/12/the-commoner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/12/the-commoner/</guid><description>Batch #11 – All Grain #6
I’m kicking off the 2011 brewing season with what I had anticipated on being my last brew of 2010. I was hoping to get this brew in before the end of the year. Unfortunately, an order shipment delay from MoreBeer followed by a month long chest cold and a grain mill debacle added up to a two month brewing hiatus.
Instead of my usual internet recipe search, I’ve decided to take another big step and develop my own recipe.</description></item><item><title>Razzmatazz</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/07/razzmatazz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/07/razzmatazz/</guid><description>I’ve been wanting to branch out from beer and try my hand at brewing mead for quite a while. Other than the suggestion that a fermented alcoholic beverage made from honey and fruit sounds delicious, I really don’t know what I’m getting into. Given that I’m in completely unknown territory here, I really don’t want to commit to a full 5 gallon batch of something I might end up not liking.</description></item><item><title>Old School</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/24/old-school/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/24/old-school/</guid><description>Batch #9 – All Grain #5
It’s time for a new recipe and all new mistakes. This is batch #2 on my v3.0 brewing system – ninth overall since I started home brewing and the fifth all-grain. This time around I’m finally tackling something that I’ve been wanting to do for almost as long as I’ve been brewing. It’s what I’ve come to call the “Vertical Epic” named after a series of beers created by Stone Brewing Co.</description></item><item><title>Back Yard Shambling</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/14/back-yard-shambling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/14/back-yard-shambling/</guid><description>It’s been a few months since my last brew. Since then, I’ve moved into a new apartment (to be closer to my brewing assistant, of course). While I still have the kitchen space and stove capacity to do my brewing inside, I’ve decided to move my brewing out of the kitchen and into the back yard. This means yet another round of upgrades to my equipment – and one of the biggest investments in new gear to date.</description></item><item><title>Arrogance, Party of Two</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/01/arrogance-party-of-two/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/01/arrogance-party-of-two/</guid><description>Batch #7 – All Grain #3 Brewed: 8-9-10
Grain Bill 15# Pale 2 Row .5# Aromatic .5# Biscuit .5# Caramunich .5# Special B Hop Schedule 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 60 minutes 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 45 minutes 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 2 minutes 5/8oz Chinook 11% AA @ 2 weeks Yeast WLP001 Misc 3.5oz. American Oak Cubes @ 1 week Brew Stats Boil: 90 minutes Mash: 60 minutes Strike Temperature: 162° Mash Temperature:154° Sparge Temperature: 168° Vitals O.</description></item><item><title>El Jefe – American Hefeweizen</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/11/07/el-jefe-american-hefeweizen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/11/07/el-jefe-american-hefeweizen/</guid><description>Batch #6 – All Grain #2 (05-02-10)
The American Homebrewers Association celebrates National Homebrew Day with an event called Big Brew. It is held on the first Saturday of May each year. The idea is that you get a group together and everyone around the world who is participating brews at the same time. The AHA has a section of their site dedicated to tracking participants and the overall results of the event.</description></item><item><title>Scottish Zombie Jesus</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/09/22/scottish-zombie-jesus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/09/22/scottish-zombie-jesus/</guid><description>Batch #5 – All Grain #1.
Brewed: 04-04-10
This is my first all grain batch and my second to be kegged. I begin my recipe search as I most often do – by browsing the recipe database at HBT. Once again, I know I’m going to go with a recipe in a style I haven’t done before. This time I am picking the Scotch Ale style, a strong ale with a strong smoky malt profile.</description></item><item><title>Pretty Good Year</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/06/20/pretty-good-year/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/06/20/pretty-good-year/</guid><description>My last vacation back to Missouri was for Thanksgiving last year. Here is a short video composed of snippets of footage I shot while spending time with the family. Everything was shot with a Canon 5D Mark II outfitted with a Canon EF 24-70mm f/2.8L USM Lens and then edited together with Final Cut Pro on a MacBook Pro.
Thanksgiving 2009 from Josh Farr on Vimeo.
Also – the Flickr Set from the trip.</description></item><item><title>Great Lakes Edmund Fitzgerald Porter Clone</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/04/22/great-lakes-edmund-fitzgerald-porter-clone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/04/22/great-lakes-edmund-fitzgerald-porter-clone/</guid><description>This is batch #3.
My goal with each new batch of beer is to do something I’ve never done before. I use this experimentation as a way explore and learn about the world of beer and brewing. There are usually several new things that I introduce each time I brew, but overall I try to limit the variables to a small extent in order to help me understand the role that each one plays.</description></item><item><title>Valentine’s Edition Brew Day – Bell’s Two Hearted Ale</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/02/19/valentines-edition-brew-day-bells-two-hearted-ale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/02/19/valentines-edition-brew-day-bells-two-hearted-ale/</guid><description>So, technically, the brew was on the day after Valentine’s Day (or as it is affectionately known around the house since it coincides with the Chinese New Year, Loony FatChoyintine’s Day). The ingredients were sourced on the most special of holidays, though.
Bell’s Two Hearted Ale is an IPA brewed by Bell’s out of Kalamazoo, Michigan. Unfortunately, it isn’t available on the west coast. My first introduction to it was through a visit to the Patton Alley Pub during my vacation back home in Springfield, Missouri.</description></item><item><title>Game Time Grub – Hot Wings</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/02/07/game-time-grub-hot-wings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/02/07/game-time-grub-hot-wings/</guid><description>These are hands down, the best wings I’ve ever made. Never mind that the recipe was hastily hacked together from multiple online recipe sources and only used as a rough guideline once in the kitchen. And don’t even think of bringing up the fact that I’m basing this on a sample size of one and have never actually made hot wings before. Caveats in mind, here it is.
Sauce
1 cup Greek yogurt 1/4 cup crumbled Bleu cheese 2 tbsp finely grated red onion Wings</description></item><item><title>Battle Royale – Flickr vs. Smugmug</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/12/22/battle-royale-flickr-vs-smugmug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/12/22/battle-royale-flickr-vs-smugmug/</guid><description>I spent a year with a pro Smugmug subscription. When it came time for renewal, I decided to make the switch
over to Flickr. In my year with Smugmug I had uploaded somewhere around 1500 photos. It would be no easy task to
migrate this number of images between services while maintaining their organization and associated metadata. So why do it and is it really worth it?
The target audience of Smugmug seems to be professional photographers.</description></item><item><title>The Belgian Blonde</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/12/22/the-belgian-blonde/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/12/22/the-belgian-blonde/</guid><description>This is my second batch of craft home brewed beer. When I set out to pick the recipe this time around I had several goals in mind. Based on my experiences the first time, I knew I wanted to expand on the knowledge and techniques I had used so far. It needed to be an even bigger beer. Instead of using dry yeast it had to be a liquid variety and use a proper starter.</description></item><item><title>Black/White</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/07/06/blackwhite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/07/06/blackwhite/</guid><description>The end of June marks the end of the first half of a year in pictures. It also signifies the end of a month-long experiment in black &amp;amp; white photography for my 365 project. I’ve never really appreciated working in the B&amp;amp;W format. If anything, I prefer to treat my images with a dialed down vibrance setting (a control available in Adobe Lightroom which applies a much smarter algorithmic approach to desaturation) in order to mute colors without removing them completely.</description></item><item><title>Brewcraft</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/06/14/brewcraft/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/06/14/brewcraft/</guid><description>My homebrew adventure began with a trip to the local supply shop, San Francisco Brewcraft.
After a few weeks of internet research I had a pretty good idea of what I needed to get started. Most of the necessary equipment is typically
packaged up into custom kits sold by just about every brewing store around. I settled on a mid-range kit composed of a 6.5 gallon plastic primary fermenting bucket (with spigot), 5 gallon glass carboy secondary fermenter, stoppers, airlocks, cleaning brushes, hose, funnel, bottle caps and capper, auto-siphon, hydrometer, and the ingredients for the first batch of beer.</description></item><item><title>The Mother Road</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/06/01/the-mother-road/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/06/01/the-mother-road/</guid><description>At the end of April, I took a bit of vacation time and spent five days driving from San Francisco, CA to my hometown of Springfield, MO. While large portions of the journey were spent mindlessly blazing down the interstate on autopilot, some sections were devoted to sightseeing along the historic Route 66. The 2300 mile adventure was a trip back through eras long past.
Oatman, Arizona (population ~128) represents an early 20th century gold mining town turned tourist destination nestled in the Black Mountains.</description></item><item><title>Concert Roundup</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/concert-roundup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/concert-roundup/</guid><description>The greatest shows are often put on by those bands that most of your friends have never heard of playing in small dives. Jason Webley started busking on the streets of Seattle with his distinctive brand of accordion music. He now tours venues around the world on his own and as part of his Monsters of Accordion tour, which showcases a number of other talented accordion musicians. He recently headlined a show with Sxip Shirey of the gypsy-folk-punk band Luminescent Orchestrii at the Bottom of the Hill in San Francisco.</description></item><item><title>Mexico</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/mexico/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/mexico/</guid><description>As I’m preparing to embark on a new road trip to the Midwest, I’m reflecting on other past trips. This post has been sitting as a draft for a few months now. It’s about time it finally got polished up and published.
I kept a short journal of the first few days of my vacation in Mexico near the small fishing village of Teacapan. This is how it starts…
It was a 4AM wake up call and I had a 6AM flight from SFO to Phoenix.</description></item><item><title>Pano</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/22/pano/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/22/pano/</guid><description>Less than a mile’s walk from my front door are the Buena Vista and Corona Heights parks. Albeit, a mile of steep hill climbing, the views of the city from the top are well worth it. I’ve recently created a few panoramas from photos taken at these locations. Hopefully they give a sense of the expansive city scenery below. Each image is linked to the full resolution version.
This image was merged from two shots taken from a street corner on Buena Vista East.</description></item><item><title>Inanimate February</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/05/inanimate-february/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/05/inanimate-february/</guid><description>Another month into the year means that many more days of 365 pictures. February was filled with rainy days. It’s a fact that can be evidenced by the large number of shots of (mostly) inanimate household objects. The limited opportunities for shooting excursions often challenged me to find interesting material in my local environment.
There was also ample occasion for pushing my post processing knowledge as well as continuing to develop my skills behind the lens.</description></item><item><title>Pillow Talk</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/19/pillow-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/19/pillow-talk/</guid><description>Almost everyone has hated Valentine’s Day at one time or another in their life. It’s most likely out of these deep feelings of love scorned masked by a disdain for corporate holidays that the great Pillow Fight was borne. This year marked the fourth anniversary of the San Francisco Pillow Fight. The rules were simple. You should bring a pillow to the Justin Herman Plaza at the Embarcadero in San Francisco on Valentine’s Day.</description></item><item><title>Year of the Ox</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/16/year-of-the-ox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/16/year-of-the-ox/</guid><description>The Chinese New Year Parade was started sometime in the 1860’s and remains one of the few night illuminated parades in the country. By now it carries strong corporate sponsorship, falling under the direction of the Chinese Chamber of Commerce – currently sponsored by Southwest Airlines.
The highlight of the parade is the 200 foot Golden Dragon also known as Gum Lung. It takes a team of over 100 to operate this illuminated monster as it winds its way along the parade route.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Pictures</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/31/everyday-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/31/everyday-pictures/</guid><description>2009 marks the beginning of my first full year of serious dSLR photography. I picked up my first dSLR camera kit – the Canon Digital Rebel XTi – in April of 2008. Since then I’ve already acquired various new lenses and other essential photo gear. Most recently I upgraded to the Canon 5D Mark II camera body. With a shooting capacity of around 400 RAW images on a 4GB card, the XTi was a great place to start with learning the photography basics.</description></item><item><title>The Big Damn Lie</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/28/the-big-damn-lie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/28/the-big-damn-lie/</guid><description>Vermillion Lies with Reverend Peyton’s Big Damn Band The Great American Music Hall Thursday, January 22nd, 2009
Established in 1907, The Great American Music Hall is San Francisco’s oldest nightclub. It is located on O’Farrell Street in the Tenderloin district. Getting to the venue is a simple matter – just take any Market Street bus to Van Ness and then any Van Ness bus to O’Farrell Street. It is a short walk further and just down the street from the also famous Mitchell Brothers O’Farrell Theatre.</description></item><item><title>And You Smell Like One Too</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/23/and-you-smell-like-one-too/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/23/and-you-smell-like-one-too/</guid><description>Continuing the field testing of my new Mark II, I decided to check off another item on my list of must visit locations and headed to the San Francisco Zoo. Getting there is a fairly trivial task – a simple matter of hopping on an outbound Muni L Taraval LRV and taking it all the way to the end. The line ends near the Great Highway which runs parallel to Ocean Beach right next to the zoo.</description></item><item><title>Shh, It’s a Secret</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/18/shh-its-a-secret/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/18/shh-its-a-secret/</guid><description>I recently read about a place known as the “secret sidewalk” located somewhere in the Niles Canyon area of the East Bay. Also in the area adjacent to this sidewalk were said to be the ruins of an old brick factory. Having recently acquired my upgraded camera body, this seemed a perfect location to break it in.
With unseasonably warm weather for mid-January reaching the mid 60’s, we set out on Saturday morning.</description></item><item><title>2022 Week 35 - Burmese -</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-35-burmese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-35-burmese/</guid><description/></item><item><title>24 Hours - Pizza</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-4-24-hours/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-4-24-hours/</guid><description>Italian Sausage &amp;amp; Mushroom Pie
24 hour cold ferment dough, 57% hydration Home ground sausage (seasoned 24 hours before grinding) Homemade fresh mozzarella (less than an hour) Dough &amp;amp; FSWY sauce recipe from &amp;ldquo;The Elements of Pizza&amp;rdquo;. The book has dough hydration levels calibrated for a home oven (70%). Since I cook my pies in an Ooni Pro, I adjusted the dough for the much hotter and faster cooking time. The sausage recipe is the hot Italian seasoning mix from The Food Lab book.</description></item><item><title>5 Ingredients or Less - Smash Burger + 3 Ingredient Mac &amp; Cheese</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-20-5-ingredients-or-less/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-20-5-ingredients-or-less/</guid><description>Smash burger, per SE - http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2014/03/ultra-smashed-cheeseburger-recipe-food-lab.html</description></item><item><title>52 Weeks of Cooking</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/</guid><description>52 Weeks of Cooking There is a sub-reddit called r/52weeksofcooking that provides a cooking prompt each week. (There is one specifically for baking too). The prompts can be specific ingredients, techniques, cuisines, or other inspirations. While I don&amp;rsquo;t partipate in the social media aspect, I&amp;rsquo;ve followed the prompts off and on over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve found it&amp;rsquo;s a fun and challenging way to keep pushing myself to continue practicing, learning, and trying new things in the kitchen.</description></item><item><title>Alphabet - BPT (Breaded Pork Tenderloin)</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-14-alphabet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-14-alphabet/</guid><description>The BPT is a popular sandwich from the Midwest (claimed by either Iowa or Indiana, depending on who you ask).
It&amp;rsquo;s a pretty straightforward construction. For the tenderloin: cut about 1/4# of pork tenderloin, butterfly it, pound it out to about 1/4&amp;quot; thick, standard 3 part breading (seasoned flour, egg, panko bread crumbs), and shallow fry a couple minutes per side. For the sandwich: soft bun, mayo, mustard, iceberg, pickles, tomatoes, onion.</description></item><item><title>American Midwest - BPT</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-35-american-midwest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-35-american-midwest/</guid><description>The BPT, or the Breaded Pork Tenderloin sandwich. Simple, yet delicious. Slice a pork tenderloin on a steep bias into 3 or 4 pieces. Pound each chunk into a large uniformly thin piece, around 1/4&amp;quot; thick. Traditional 3 step breading station - flour, cayenne, salt &amp;amp; pepper followed by egg and finished with panko bread crumbs. Shallow fry for 2-3 minutes per side. Serve on a basic bun - I chose a pub-style bun, which is almost too fancy - simpler really is better for this one.</description></item><item><title>Australasian - Halal Snack Pack</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-25-australasian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-25-australasian/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s just a Jackson Pollock of awesome bad food. Fermented french fries, shredded sharp cheddar, doner kebab chicken, garlic mayo, bbq sauce, sirracha.
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Halal_snack_pack</description></item><item><title>Avocado - Guacamole</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-50-avocado/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-50-avocado/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Baking - Baked Manicotti</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-24-baking-baked-manicotti/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-24-baking-baked-manicotti/</guid><description>Baked Manicotti. Noodles stuffed with ricotta and zucchini, smothered with tomato sauce and topped with mozzarella.</description></item><item><title>Batter - Waffles</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-34-batter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-34-batter/</guid><description>Waffle. Served with bourbon maple syrup and raspberry syrup.</description></item><item><title>Beans - White Bean Gratin / Chili Mac</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-15-beans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-15-beans/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s red &amp;amp; white all over? A bean week double feature, of course. First up, a gratin made of white beans, kale, and shaved fennel root. The recipe comes from: https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2012/11/swiss-chard-fennel-white-bean-gratin-recipe.html</description></item><item><title>Berries - Blueberry BBQ Sauce</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-26-berries/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-26-berries/</guid><description>Blueberry BBQ Sauce - http://www.vindulge.com/2017/06/grilled-chicken-blackberry-bbq-sauce-recipe-video-northwest/</description></item><item><title>Black and White - Bibimbap</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-24-black-and-white/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-24-black-and-white/</guid><description>From the bottom up:
Seasoned sushi rice reheated in a cast iron with sesame oil to mimic a dolsot Carrot &amp;amp; asparagus cut into matchsticks and sauteed with garlic &amp;amp; ginger Homemade kimchi (roughly based on - https://www.foodiewithfamily.com/easy-fast-kimchi-mak-kimchi-recipe/) Sliced cucumber (salt, let stand, rinse, squeeze out water) Bibimbap sauce (gochujang, sugar, water, sesame oil) Fried egg Black sesame seeds</description></item><item><title>Black and White - Three Shades of B&amp;W</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-7-black-and-white/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-7-black-and-white/</guid><description>Black Olive Tapenade &amp;amp; Feta Crostini
Here&amp;rsquo;s a little snack to start things off. I kept the tapenade vegetarian and added a splash of soy sauce as a sad attempt to compensate for the lack of anchovies. If I&amp;rsquo;d had marmite, that might have worked too. As a cruel joke, the feta is not vegetarian, having animal rennet in its ingredient list.
Just before making the tapenade, I was using the food processor to make hot sauce.</description></item><item><title>Braising - Chile Colorado &amp; Braised Vegetable Tacos</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-7-braising/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-7-braising/</guid><description>Chile Colorado from Aaron Sanchez recipe - https://www.vice.com/en_us/article/ywan8w/chile-con-carne-colorado-style-burritos-recipe Shredded &amp;amp; sauce adjustments as suggested by - https://www.reddit.com/r/mexicanfood/comments/f2qyv4/long_time_lurker_first_time_poster_my_take_on/
Yucatan-style habanero pickled red onions - https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2016/05/yucatan-style-red-onion-pickle-sour-orange-recipe.html
(I didn&amp;rsquo;t have all of the citrus, so I just used a combination of lime juice and apple cider vinegar instead)
Robert Rodriguez flour tortilla recipe - https://www.food.com/recipe/robert-rodriguez-sin-city-breakfast-tacos-234530
Topped with cotija cheese, sliced radish, avocado lime cream, and cilantro</description></item><item><title>Brazilian - Churrasco con Chimichurri</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-9-brazilian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-9-brazilian/</guid><description>Flank steak with chimichurri. The chimichurri is cilantro, parsley, shallot, garlic, red pepper flakes, lemon juice, red wine vinegar, salt, pepper, and olive oil. No measurements, just toss a bunch of stuff in a food processor and chop it up. Save adding the olive oil until the end.</description></item><item><title>British - Bangers &amp; Mash</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-15-british/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-15-british/</guid><description>Recipe roughly from - http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2012/10/bangers-and-mash-with-onion-gravy-recipe.html Didn&amp;rsquo;t have regular milk for the potatoes. Used leftover buttermilk from last week&amp;rsquo;s fried chicken plus a splash of soy milk. Creamy mash with a mild tang from the buttermilk. And that. Onion. Gravy.</description></item><item><title>Cafeteria Food - Mashed Potatoes</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-17-cafeteria-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-17-cafeteria-food/</guid><description>Was sick this week so I phoned this one in (just like real cafeteria food! ba dum tss).</description></item><item><title>Cakes - Pancakes</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-52-cakes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-52-cakes/</guid><description>And that&amp;rsquo;s a wrap. My flair might not reflect it, but I managed to turn out a dish for every single week this year. Some great ones, some real duds, some that took a ton of effort, some themes I hated at the time, and some I just phoned in.</description></item><item><title>California Cuisine - Terrible Noodles</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-25-california-cuisine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-25-california-cuisine/</guid><description>Thai-inspired Terrible Noodle Bowl. The noodles were terrible. I&amp;rsquo;ve never cooked rice noodles before. I guess they needed rinsed more. And then some more. And then a bunch more.</description></item><item><title>Cartoon - Bob's Burgers</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-30-cartoon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-30-cartoon/</guid><description>The first of 3 burger experiences, two burgers each. One 80/20 ground beef and the other ground Impossible. These are all taken from the Bob&amp;rsquo;s Burgers cookbook.
The &amp;ldquo;Chevre Which Way But Loose Burger&amp;rdquo;. Garlic infused patty, Herbed (Sage, Oregano, Thyme, Rosemary) chevre/tomato/cucumber/mayonnaise spread, sliced cucumber, red onion.
Final verdict? These are all fun novelty burgers. None of them are bad, but they won&amp;rsquo;t be the best burger you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had either.</description></item><item><title>Casseroles - Lasagna Roll Ups</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-42-casseroles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-42-casseroles/</guid><description>Splat. The lasagna roll up. Instead of layers, lay the noodle out, put filling on it, roll the noodle up. Recipe based on - https://www.cookingclassy.com/spinach-four-cheese-lasagna-roll-ups/ The only cheese I had was a block of mozzarella. So I just shredded that up and used it. I had the no boil kind of noodles. I just soaked them in hot water until they were workable.</description></item><item><title>Charcuterie</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-30-charcuterie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-30-charcuterie/</guid><description>Tried out some fancy cheese and salami served on a piece of wood. Beecher&amp;rsquo;s No Woman cheese made with raisins and jerk spices, Rogue Creamery&amp;rsquo;s Crater Lake Blue, Cowgirl Creamery&amp;rsquo;s Humboldt Fog, Olympia Provisions Loukanika Salami.</description></item><item><title>Chowder - Spicy Corn Chowder</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-4-chowder-spicy-corn-chowder/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-4-chowder-spicy-corn-chowder/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Cordless Station</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/cordless-station/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/cordless-station/</guid><description>Once I accumulated enough cordless tools*, I needed a centralized place to store them all (That reminds me of a classic George Carlin bit about &amp;ldquo;stuff&amp;rdquo;. The more stuff you have, the more space you need to keep it). This was a quick weekend project with a bit of scrap plywood, an idea, and not much else of a plan. I did a bit of online searching to get some ideas of form factors and inspiration and then headed into the shop to make a mess.</description></item><item><title>Crunchy - Roasted Chickpeas</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-23-crunchy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-23-crunchy/</guid><description>Dried chickpeas soaked overnight, drained &amp;amp; dried, tossed in salt &amp;amp; olive oil and roasted on a sheet pan at 400F for 35 minutes. Tossed with cayenne, paprika, and a squeeze of lime. Turns out these probably should have been roasted longer. There were some good crunchy darker ones, but there were a good percentage that were under done. Even simple seeming things like these are harder than they look sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Cucumbers - Gazpacho &amp; Cucumber Salads</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-31-cucumbers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-31-cucumbers/</guid><description>A few different experiments this week. First up, Cucumber Gazpacho: https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/cucumber-tomatillo-gazpacho This is an interesting one. At first it tasted really good, but after a few bites it got really hard to keep eating. It has a very aggressive flavor profile that I don&amp;rsquo;t think makes it work for a main dish. It would be fine as a small starter portion or as sauce served alongside something else (like maybe pork tenderloin).</description></item><item><title>Cutting Board</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/cutting-board/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/cutting-board/</guid><description>Every woodworker has to make at least one cutting board in their career. This is my first and the one that I take up space with on my kitchen counter. I made it from the same Hard Maple that I used for the Kitchen Island. It has grooves carved out on the sides for picking it up and rubber feet screwed into the bottom to keep it secure on the counter surface.</description></item><item><title>Deep Cuts</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/deep-cuts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/deep-cuts/</guid><description>Welcome to the deep cuts. Over 2+ decades, you develop some portfolio cruft. These are some of the bits and bobs that I&amp;rsquo;ve toiled and tinkered with over the years. There are some outdated and ocasionally cringeworthy technology choices, but also some bits that I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of for what they were at the time.
Personal Projects These are all projects I have worked on in my spare time for myself (such as this website), friends, or as learning experiences.</description></item><item><title>Deep Frying - Hush Puppies / Chimichangas</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-13-deep-frying/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-13-deep-frying/</guid><description>Hush Puppies
I didn&amp;rsquo;t have my frying oil temperature dialed in. Some got a bit darker than ideal. And some of them were a bit more mishapen than others. Still taste the same though.
1c cornmeal 1/2c flour 1tbsp sugar 2tsp baking powder 1/4tsp cayenne 1tsp salt grated onion 1/2 milk 1tsp hot sauce 1/4tsp garlic powder</description></item><item><title>Deli Foods - Deviled Eggs</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-39-deli-foods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-39-deli-foods/</guid><description>The Devil&amp;rsquo;s Eggs. Spiced up with a dash of homemade ghost pepper hot sauce and a sprinkle of fresh ground Maule&amp;rsquo;s Red cayenne powder</description></item><item><title>Dim Sum - Spring Rolls</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-29-dim-sum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-29-dim-sum/</guid><description>This is the recipe I used as a guide: http://steamykitchen.com/22276-chinese-spring-rolls-with-chicken-recipe.html I stuffed these with a mixture of ground chicken, and shredded carrot &amp;amp; broccoli. What I thought was a bag of regular pre-shredded cabbage &amp;amp; carrots from Trader Joes turned out to be broccoli slaw. I also tossed in a bit of extra pre-shredded carrot. I just pulsed boneless/skinless chicken thighs in the food processor to make the ground chicken.</description></item><item><title>Dining Room Table</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/dining-room-table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/dining-room-table/</guid><description>This was a fairly early project in my woodworking career. I found the plans on one of the many DIY blogs that feature these kinds of budget Restoration Hardware style pieces. The material is all standard cheap big box store material - 2x4&amp;rsquo;s, 4x4&amp;rsquo;s, and pine boards. The joinery is pocket hole screws and biscuits.</description></item><item><title>Dorm Food - Meatball Sub</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-12-dorm-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-12-dorm-food/</guid><description>Once upon a time when I lived in a dorm, there were Subway Sundays. It was a 2 for 1 deal or some such so I&amp;rsquo;d get a couple of fully loaded meatball subs to last me for a few meals. Attempted to recreate a homemade version here. Tried this bread recipe: https://www.favfamilyrecipes.com/subway-bread/ and just kind of winged a basic meatball and marinara recipe.</description></item><item><title>Drill Press Stand</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/drill-press-stand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/drill-press-stand/</guid><description>The drill press stand came about at the same time as the sanding station. They were both born of the same set of frustrations and focus on improving shop organization and functionality. In both cases, tools were taking up otherwise valuable real estate and in a way that made them difficult or less safe to use. I also had the opportunity to consolidate storage spaces based on function. Here, I could keep everything related to drilling holes all in one place.</description></item><item><title>Emulsification - Vinaigrette</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-29-emulsification/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-29-emulsification/</guid><description>Now, you could follow a real recipe like this: https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2014/10/simple-vinaigrette-recipe.html But if I just want a quick single serving of salad dressing, this is how I do it. The most important part is the 3:1 ratio of vinegar &amp;amp; oil. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be an exact fussy measurement. I start with vinegar, 2 parts neutral oil, 1 part olive oil. The oil will float on top, so it&amp;rsquo;s easy to eyeball the amount.</description></item><item><title>Escoffier - Eggs Benedict (+Florentine)</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-13-escoffier/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-13-escoffier/</guid><description>Eggs Florentine (English muffin, sauteed spinach, poached egg, hollandaise, cayenne, parsley) &amp;amp; Eggs Benedict (replace spinach w/ Canadian bacon). Hollandaise is Serious Eats 2 minute recipe - egg yolk, salt, water, lemon juice, stick blender, and a stick of butter.</description></item><item><title>Fad Food - Double Decker Taco</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-48-fad-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-48-fad-food/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fermented - Kimchi Fried Chicken/Tofu Sandwich</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-10-fermented/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-10-fermented/</guid><description>Kenji&amp;rsquo;s Recipe - https://www.seriouseats.com/2019/07/kimchi-fried-chicken-sandwich.html
This is a fun take on fried chicken and of course delicious - it&amp;rsquo;s fried chicken, why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be? The combination of red chili glaze and the spice mix sprinkled on after frying makes this extra spicy. Some people in the recipe comments complained about ROI based on the amount of effort to make it. I didn&amp;rsquo;t think it was terribly more involved than making regular fried chicken.</description></item><item><title>Finnish - Korvapuusti (Cinnamon Buns)</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-32-finnish/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-32-finnish/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not even going to bother with plating and presentation. These came out a hot mess. Dough came out better than I&amp;rsquo;ve done in a while, but otherwise my baking skills continue to suck. Regardless how they look, they do taste great. Sugar, cinnamon, freshly ground green cardamom - why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t they?
Buns: https://www.thespruceeats.com/finnish-cinnamon-pastries-korvapuusti-2952710
Pearl Sugar: https://whilehewasnapping.com/2015/02/how-to-diy-pearl-sugar/</description></item><item><title>Flour - Beignets</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-21-flour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-21-flour/</guid><description>Recipe from - https://www.billyparisi.com/the-best-authentic-new-orleans-beignets-recipe/
I thought these were going to be a fail. The dough seemed way too sticky and I just kept adding more flour while the mixer continued to knead. Also the oil I was frying in was pretty shallow. Despite all of that, they&amp;rsquo;re actually just ok. Maybe a little chewier and unevenly cooked in some spots than ideal, but even a bad doughnut is still a doughnut.</description></item><item><title>Food in Disguise - Vegan Chicken &amp; Waffles</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-33-food-in-disguise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-33-food-in-disguise/</guid><description>Source: https://www.rabbitandwolves.com/vegan-chicken-and-waffles-with-spicy-maple-syrup/
I tend to find vegan cooking to be very idiosyncratic or maybe even esoteric with a lot of recipe constructions compared to their non-vegan counterparts. This pair is no exception with its huge amount of cornstarch, ground flax seeds, and vinegar curdled almond milk.
Despite the deep frying, a lot of the excessive cornstarch coating on the chickpea fritters stayed as white flakes. Flavor-wise, they&amp;rsquo;re actually pretty good - crispy outside, but still light and fluffy on the inside - not too dense or too crunchy.</description></item><item><title>From Scratch - Fettuccine with Pork Meatball Sugo</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-17-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-17-from-scratch/</guid><description>Homemade noodles and a slow simmered sugo with pork sausage meatballs made from home ground pork shoulder. I just used the dough recipe right in the pasta roller manual. Every food blog has about the same recipe. It&amp;rsquo;s just flour, eggs, salt and water. I don&amp;rsquo;t have an exact recipe for the sugo, it&amp;rsquo;s more of a template. Measurements are generally just a guess.
4oz pancetta, finely diced (1 Trader Joe&amp;rsquo;s package or some equivalent amount) olive oil unsalted butter mirepoix 1 yellow onion, finely diced 3 celery ribs, finely diced 2 carrots, finely diced herb boquette 1 bay leaf</description></item><item><title>Garlic - Garlic Knots</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-27-garlic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-27-garlic/</guid><description>Garlic Knots, whole roasted garlic, and marinara dipping sauce. Bread recipe from - http://bakerbynature.com/homemade-garlic-knots/</description></item><item><title>Ginger - Vegetable &amp; Beef Stir Fry</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-18-ginger/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-18-ginger/</guid><description>Terrible pictures this week. Not that any of the rest have been winners. It&amp;rsquo;s just a basic ginger beef &amp;amp; vegetable stir fry served over brown rice. No real recipe I followed, but I recommend this for guidelines - https://www.reddit.com/r/Cooking/comments/b0zql0/basic_techniques_how_to_make_any_chinese_stir_fry/</description></item><item><title>Guilty Pleasures - Spaghetti with Creamy Tomato Sauce</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-49-guilty-pleasures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-49-guilty-pleasures/</guid><description>Spaghetti in a creamy red tomato sauce. Carbs, heavy cream, butter - that&amp;rsquo;s gotta count as a guilty pleasure, right?</description></item><item><title>Handheld Foods - Calzone</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-44-handheld-foods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-44-handheld-foods/</guid><description>I still had some items leftover from last week&amp;rsquo;s casserole, so I repurposed them into calzones. Filling is made of mushrooms, onions, veggie sausage, ricotta, mozarella. Recipe based on - http://www.simplyscratch.com/2012/02/homemade-pizza-calzones.html</description></item><item><title>Hindsight 2020 - Kugel</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-1-hindsight-2020/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-1-hindsight-2020/</guid><description>In hindsight, I wish I could find my mom&amp;rsquo;s recipe. This is this one - https://www.epicurious.com/recipes/food/views/Browned-Onion-Kugels-231507 It&amp;rsquo;s not the one I remember (every Jewish grandmother must have their own recipe), but it&amp;rsquo;s a good basic version. By cooking in a muffin tray, you get more of the brown crusty bits in an easy to serve format. The onions already bring a lot of sweetness to it, but you could easily tweak it more toward the savory or sweet side with minor adjustments or additions.</description></item><item><title>Inspired by Magic - Beans, the Magical Fruit</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-31-inspired-by-magic/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-31-inspired-by-magic/</guid><description>Vegetarian frito pie. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t dare call it &amp;ldquo;chili&amp;rdquo;. Canned black and red kidney beans. Recipe from: http://www.tastyeverafter.com/vegetarian-chili-frito-pie/</description></item><item><title>Inspired By Music - Scrambled Eggs</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-51-inspired-by-music/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-51-inspired-by-music/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Italian - Pork Sugo &amp; Pappardelle</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-6-italian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-6-italian/</guid><description>Papardelle with Pork Sugo Here&amp;rsquo;s the finished dish, garnished with grated parmigiano reggiano and chopped parsley.
The sugo and garnish were great, but the pasta was awful. I think the last time I tried to make pasta was in the 90&amp;rsquo;s. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a pasta roller, so I had to try and roll the pasta out by hand with a rolling pin. I did not succeed. I&amp;rsquo;m not even going to talk about it.</description></item><item><title>Jamaican - Jerk Tofu &amp; Chicken w/ Rice &amp; Peas</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-6-jamaican/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-6-jamaican/</guid><description>Jerk Tofu &amp;amp; Chicken w/ Rice &amp;amp; Peas
I started with the marinade from this recipe: https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2013/08/jerk-chicken.html Chicken thighs and pressed extra firm tofu were marinated (separately) overnight in vacuum sealed bags. The chicken was sous vide for 3 hours @ 165F and the tofu for 2 hours @ 180F. They were both finished in a cast iron pan in the Ooni Pro for a few minutes. I ended up not really liking the end result.</description></item><item><title>Kawaii - Upside Down Pineapple Cake</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-11-kawaii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-11-kawaii/</guid><description>This recipe is from the BraveTart book (Stella Parks from Serious Eats). It&amp;rsquo;s one of the easier ones to assemble. Pineapple, brown sugar (&amp;amp; dark rum) topping, and cake batter layered in a cast iron pan.
Stella&amp;rsquo;s example uses cute little star shaped pineapple cut outs. It&amp;rsquo;s dangerous business going out these days, so I works with what I gots. All we had was a drawer full of Halloween themed cookie cutters.</description></item><item><title>Kitchen Island</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/kitchen-island/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/kitchen-island/</guid><description>There is an area in my kitchen (the &amp;ldquo;nook&amp;rdquo;) that I&amp;rsquo;ve never been able to solve. Should there be a table, an island, built in bench seating, or outside-facing bar seats? This is the result of the island attempt (spoiler - it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the solution). I found the plans for this one off of a DIY blog somewhere. The carcasse and drawer construction is plywood. Joinery is pocket hole screws and brad nails.</description></item><item><title>Korean - Dak Bulgogi Bibimbap</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-38-korean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-38-korean/</guid><description>Bibimbap. Nothing much to it. Cook some rice. Julienne and saute some carrot and zucchini with garlic and ginger. Cook some spinach. Soak some cucumber slices in a salt water brine. Make some bibimbap sauce. Fry an egg. I used the sauce proportions from this recipe - http://www.koreanbapsang.com/2015/01/bibimbap.html</description></item><item><title>Kumiko Chest</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/kumiko-chest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/kumiko-chest/</guid><description>I started this project with two initial goals. Primarily, I had a growing stockpile of reclaimed material I wanted to use up. Additionally I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend too much time front-loading the design of the project. I knew I wanted to build a low chest of drawers and worked out an initial set of dimensions (2&amp;rsquo;x2&amp;rsquo;x4&amp;rsquo;). The rest of it, I would work out organically as the build went along.</description></item><item><title>Made Healthy - Black Bean Burgers</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-3-made-healthy-black-bean-burgers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-3-made-healthy-black-bean-burgers/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Meal Prep - Vegetable Stock</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-47-meal-prep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-47-meal-prep/</guid><description>Homemade vegetable stock. Onion, celery, carrot, mushroom, parsley, thyme, kombu, garlic, leek greens, fennel frond, bay leaf, peppercorns. Toss it all into a pressure cooker with water and cook 15 minutes on high. Strain and discard the solids. Your stock is prepped for your meal.</description></item><item><title>Memory Box</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/memory-box/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/memory-box/</guid><description>This small wooden box is made from Figured Maple and Black Walnut. This is a sentimental piece made to hold a former pet&amp;rsquo;s dog collar on the mantle. The Black Walnut pieces were resawn from thicker stock on the bandsaw. The outer Maple box with the Black Walnut top/bottom is constructed first as a single assembly. The lid is then cut out from the box and the Black Walnut wall liner pieces are added.</description></item><item><title>Middle East - Hummus</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-10-middle-east/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-10-middle-east/</guid><description>Tahini sauce. This is the recipe I started from: http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2016/03/israeli-style-extra-smooth-hummus-recipe.html</description></item><item><title>Midnight Snacks - Quesadilla</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-33-midnight-snacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-33-midnight-snacks/</guid><description>Out of the skillet and chopped into flavor-enhancing triangles.</description></item><item><title>Miso - Ramen, Pork Tenderloin, Glazed Carrots</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-2-miso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-2-miso/</guid><description>Having never cooked with miso and not really knowing anything about it, this is the one I picked at the store.
This is primarily the recipe I followed - https://umamigirl.com/easy-vegetarian-ramen/
I haven&amp;rsquo;t come across a lot of vegetarian ramen broths and I&amp;rsquo;m not extremely versed in what qualifies as good/bad/authentic ramen. Despite some minor execution miscalculations, I thought this was really quite tasty, though. Blending the rehydrated mushrooms with the stock makes for a rich and creamy broth - I don&amp;rsquo;t even think it necessarily needs the extra pat of butter at the end.</description></item><item><title>Moroccan - Kefta Sandwich</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-46-moroccan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-46-moroccan/</guid><description>Kefta sandwich. Recipe - http://thenewdaily.com.au/life/eat-drink/2014/10/08/moroccan-kefta-sandwich-recipe/</description></item><item><title>mystery-basket-generator</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/projects/mystery-basket-generator/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/projects/mystery-basket-generator/</guid><description>The original basil project was a grand vision that never existed beyond the initial prototype phase. This reincarnation is a stripped down weekend project version is a simple randomized ingredient mystery basket generator inspired by shows such as the Food Network’s Chopped series. It is a Node.js application built using the Express framework and MongoDB data store. I also whipped up a quick PHP version for generating ingredient lists for homebrew beer recipes as a later version.</description></item><item><title>Nepalese - Momos &amp; Chow Mein</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-22-nepalese/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-22-nepalese/</guid><description>Based on recipes from:
https://www.yowangdu.com/tibetan-food/momos.html https://www.vegrecipesofindia.com/veg-momos-recipe-vegetable-momos/</description></item><item><title>NoteKeeper</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/projects/notekeeper/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/projects/notekeeper/</guid><description>NoteKeeper was an experiment in creating a notekeeping application with a focus on privacy. It was designed as an Electron application with a backend written in Go. The frontend was built with Typescript, React, and Electron. It communicated with the backend using Google Protobufs.</description></item><item><title>Odyssey</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/projects/odyssey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/projects/odyssey/</guid><description>Odyssey is my game engine development playground. It is written in modern C++. While there is some functional overlap with Vertical 3D, I wanted a green space to experiment. I originally learned C++ in the mid-90&amp;rsquo;s which informs a lot of the older Vertical 3D code and its patterns. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t designed primarily as a game engine either.</description></item><item><title>Oktoberfest - Potato Salad, Sausage</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-40-oktoberfest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-40-oktoberfest/</guid><description>German potato salad and beer braised sausage with peppers and onions. It isn&amp;rsquo;t much to look at, but it sure tastes good. It really is quite surprisingly delicious for how simple it is to put together. Recipes: http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2014/10/roasted-beer-basted-pork-veal-sausages-pickles-recipe.html &amp;amp; http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2013/08/german-potato-salad.html I deviated a bit on the sausage recipe, skipping pickling the bell peppers and onions. I already had a batch of pickled banana pepper rings in the fridge and didn&amp;rsquo;t want to wait to pickle the peppers and onions.</description></item><item><title>On a Stick - Skewers</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-23-on-a-stick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-23-on-a-stick/</guid><description>On vacation in MO. Threw premade skewers from hyvee on a friend&amp;rsquo;s grill. Nothing as good as homemade skewers on the weber.</description></item><item><title>One Pot - Chickpea Masala</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-9-one-pot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-9-one-pot/</guid><description>Chickpea Masala. Garnished with cilantro &amp;amp; served with naan. I started with this Serious Eats recipe - http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2014/01/quick-easy-pressure-cooker-chicken-and-chickpea-masala.html as a basic template and just riffed a simple vegetarian version based on what I had on hand. Even this screwed up rendition was really good. I&amp;rsquo;m sure the original recipe is even better.</description></item><item><title>Peppers - Enchiladas</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-12-peppers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-12-peppers/</guid><description>Chicken Enchiladas w/ Refried Beans &amp;amp; Mexican Rice</description></item><item><title>Photography</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/photography/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/photography/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Pies - Pot Pies</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-11-pies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-11-pies/</guid><description>Individual pot pies - one veggie only and one with chicken. Crust is just a simple pie dough - flour, butter, salt, water mixed in the food processor and rolled out. Baked the pies in the oven for about 25 minutes at 375F.</description></item><item><title>Potatoes - Baked Potato</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-45-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-45-potatoes/</guid><description>Loaded baked potato. Glamorous fine dining, it ain&amp;rsquo;t. Whatever, carbs taste good.</description></item><item><title>Presentation - Breakfast Taco</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-21-presentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-21-presentation/</guid><description>Cheese crisp, masa tortilla, fried potatoes, scrambled egg, onion, pork, parsley.</description></item><item><title>Proofing - Hoagies</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-26-proofing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-26-proofing/</guid><description>Open face meatball hoagie - Bread, meatballs, marinara, parmesan, provolone, parsley.</description></item><item><title>Pumpkin - Pumpkin Ravioli</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-44-pumpkin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-44-pumpkin/</guid><description>Pumpkin ravioli with brown butter sauce, fried sage, and toasted pecans. This could have been a lot better, but I think I overworked the dough and probably burned the butter.</description></item><item><title>Puree - Hummus</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-20-puree/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-20-puree/</guid><description>Hummus. Lots of it. It&amp;rsquo;s another Kenji recipe - https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2016/03/israeli-style-extra-smooth-hummus-recipe.html</description></item><item><title>Retro Recipes - Chicken a la King</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-27-retro-recipes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-27-retro-recipes/</guid><description>For me this evokes strong memories of boxed dinners and cream of whatever canned soup-based casserole type dishes. It also resembles a pot pie filling, just served over a starch instead of stuffed in a crust and baked.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t go by an exact recipe, but here&amp;rsquo;s the rough outline of what I did. Quantities are largely approximate. Just go by what seems right proportionately and suits your own tastes. Always taste &amp;amp; season as you go.</description></item><item><title>Rice - Arancini</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-5-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-5-rice/</guid><description>From Daniel Gritzer&amp;rsquo;s SE recipe - https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2014/10/arancini-rice-balls-recipe.html
Not perfectly shaped, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t fuss too much trying to get them formed. The recipe says 12-15, but I think I ended up with 23. I used sushi rice as recommended and cooked it in the pressure cooker. The only deviation from the recipe was to keep them vegetarian, replacing chicken for vegetable stock and omitting the gelatin. I didn&amp;rsquo;t find the lack of gelatin to end up being a problem and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any need to substitute an alternative thickener.</description></item><item><title>Rice - Mexican Rice &amp; Rice Pudding</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-2-rice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-2-rice/</guid><description>I love Mexican rice as a side with refried beans. I could eat them each by themselves and be happy, but I wanted to work them directly into a dish. With refried beans, tostadas came to mind first, so I started there and built onto it with what I had on hand. All homemade - fried flour tostadas topped with refried beans, Mexican rice, brussels sprouts slaw, avocado, pickled vegetables, and chipotle chili sauce.</description></item><item><title>Rolled - Sushi</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2019/week-52-rolled-sushi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2019/week-52-rolled-sushi/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Router Table</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/router-table/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/router-table/</guid><description>This was the first cabinetry project I ever built. I followed a set of fairly thorough plans I found for free online. The carcasse is constructed from plywood. The top consists of double laminated MDF topped with black laminate and edge banded with oak. The fence is also made from MDF. The small drawers slide on wooden rails while the bottom drawers use standard metal ball bearing drawer slides. The front access door is simple oak framed around a sheet of acrylic with a scrap piece of T-track to act as as door latch.</description></item><item><title>rpi-ferment</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/projects/rpi-ferment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/projects/rpi-ferment/</guid><description>v1 This is a beer fermentation temperature monitoring, logging, and control application suite built on the Raspberry Pi platform. There are a series of blog posts detailing the entire project. The software aspect comprises two Node.js applications written in CoffeeScript. The backend server interacts with the Pi’s GPIO, capturing temperature data from any number of configured DS18B20 temperature sensors and logging them into graphite via statsd. It also exposes a RESTful API built using Express and Mongoose for managing fermentation profiles.</description></item><item><title>Russian - Beef Stroganoff, Blinis, Kvass</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-3-russian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-3-russian/</guid><description>I wasn&amp;rsquo;t planning on this dish since I remembered doing it in a previous one (2012 Week 13 - it&amp;rsquo;s been a while), but with leftover egg noodles from a few weeks ago and a Sam the Cooking Guy video popping up in my feed, the universe nudged me into it.
This is Sam&amp;rsquo;s version - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KJg4AS4uVWk But when there&amp;rsquo;s a Food Lab version, that&amp;rsquo;s the one you go with - https://www.</description></item><item><title>Salad - Smoked Chicken Arugula Salad</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-32-salad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-32-salad/</guid><description>Arugula &amp;amp; Spinach, Avocado, Pear, Tomato, Hard Boiled Egg, Smoked Chicken, Cornbread Croutons, Buttermilk Lime Dressing.</description></item><item><title>Salt - Blistered Pepperoncini Peppers</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-41-salt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-41-salt/</guid><description>This is the same process as Spanish-style blistered Padron peppers, but with pepperoncini peppers instead. It&amp;rsquo;s dead simple. Just get a cast iron pan with a bit of oil smoking hot and cook the peppers just a minute or two until they blister. Toss with some good olive oil and sprinkle with salt. Done.</description></item><item><title>Sanding Station</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/sanding-station/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/sanding-station/</guid><description>I have two stationary sanding tools - an oscillating drum sander and a combination belt/disc sander. They&amp;rsquo;re both benchtop models on the cheaper end of the spectrum (Chinese import tool company Wen - for my limited hobby use, they make some surprisingly decent lower budget tools). Originally I just made space for them on the counter tops, but that was never an ideal solution.
I had essentially 3 problems:
I have two different sanding machines taking up a lot of real estate on my cabinet counters They&amp;rsquo;re difficult to access and use both safely and ergonomically All of my sanding tools and materials are scattered around the shop The answer to all of these was to build this new sanding station.</description></item><item><title>Screw-Ups Revisited - Smoked Boston Baked Beans</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-1-screw-ups-revisited/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-1-screw-ups-revisited/</guid><description>Adapted from: http://amazingribs.com/recipes/beans/boston_baked_beans.html
I used 1/2# of dried pinto beans, soaked overnight. Divided into a smaller vegetarian batch using water (didn&amp;rsquo;t have any vegetable broth on hand) and a larger batch using pancetta and chicken stock (1c super gelatinous homemade stock and 1c store-bought low sodium broth).
The first time I tried making these back in July, I put them in the smoker with a pork butt at 225F. The beans were in the smoker around 9 hours.</description></item><item><title>Shop Cabinets</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/shop-cabinets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/shop-cabinets/</guid><description>The shop cabinets are based on the Miter Station plans from The Wood Whisperer with only minor modifications. I needed to build one fewer cabinet to fit my space. I finished the top with sheets of black laminate (glued down with Super 77) to match my router table, omitted the t-tracks and used poplar for the edge banding. The drawer faces are made from scraps of reclaimed pine from a set of old built-in shelving in my basement.</description></item><item><title>Shot Capture</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/projects/shot-capture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/projects/shot-capture/</guid><description>Shot Capture is a tool designed to remotely control a DSLR camera and record single hi-resolution RAW images to disk. It is meant to be used in conjunction with a motion controller rig. The recorded images can later be processed and combined to create HD video sequences. Github Repo</description></item><item><title>Sortimo Cart</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/sortimo-cart/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/workshop/sortimo-cart/</guid><description>Over my time making I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated a lot of different &amp;ldquo;hardware&amp;rdquo;. Nuts, bolts, washers, screws, assorted mechanical fasteners, electrical connectors and components. All sorts of the different bits and bobs you pick up from project to project along with all your normal staples (and actual staples too probably). Once I got tired of just a mess of parts boxes inside of cabinet drawers, I decided that part of the solution was to switch to some sort of compartmentalized storage bins.</description></item><item><title>Soul Food - Pulled Pork Mac &amp; Cheese</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-28-soul-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-28-soul-food/</guid><description>Kenji&amp;rsquo;s 3 ingredient mac &amp;amp; cheese - https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2017/01/3-ingredient-stovetop-mac-and-cheese-recipe.html Add carnitas (Sous vide recipe - https://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2017/01/sous-vide-carnitas-crispy-mexican-style-pulled-pork-recipe.html), a few splashes of cholula and parsley to finish.</description></item><item><title>South African - Bunny Chow</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-16-south-african/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-16-south-african/</guid><description>Chicken, chickpea, and potato curry served in a hollowed out bread pocket.
Curry recipe from - https://www.africanbites.com/bunny-chow/ Bread recipe from - https://www.handletheheat.com/homemade-bread-bowls/
For a thicker curry, stir in a cornstarch slurry (start with 1tsp) near the end. To keep it vegan, kick out the chicken and substitute more vegetables - carrots, bell peppers, peas, whatever.
Downscaled to half volume recipe to make 3 small loaves.</description></item><item><title>Southern - Fried Chicken + Sides</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-14-southern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-14-southern/</guid><description>Southern Fried Chicken - http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2015/07/the-food-lab-southern-fried-chicken-recipe.html Hushpuppies &amp;amp; Remoulade - http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2014/03/buttermilk-hushpuppies-remoulade-recipe.html BBQ Beans - http://www.seriouseats.com/2014/06/the-best-barbecue-beans-quick-and-slow-cooked.html Deli Slaw - http://amazingribs.com/recipes/slaws_salads_and_other_vegetables/creamy_coleslaw_with_sour_cream.html Asparagus &amp;amp; Hollandaise - http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2013/04/foolproof-2-minute-hollandaise-recipe.html Macaroni Salad - No recipe. Just cook some elbows, chop some bell pepper, celery &amp;amp; onion. Make a dressing kind of like the slaw.</description></item><item><title>Spice Blends - Tikka Masala</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-8-spice-blends/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-8-spice-blends/</guid><description>Paneer tikka masala and chicken tikka masala served with some very plain naan.</description></item><item><title>Sri Lankan - Parippu</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-19-sri-lankan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-19-sri-lankan/</guid><description>Red lentils (dhal) &amp;amp; Coconut Curry Garnished with cilantro and a splash of lime and served with a piece of warm naan.
This is super simple and crazy delicious. Plus it&amp;rsquo;s vegan. A couple points of reference: http://berrychik.com/sri-lankan-parippu-masoor-dal-recipe/ https://www.196flavors.com/sri-lanka-parippu-curry/ There are some things that I don&amp;rsquo;t have readily on hand like curry leaves or saffron powder. I order things a bit differently too - toast whole spices in oil, add &amp;amp; sautee aromatics (onion, chile, garlic), bloom ground spices, add rinsed uncooked lentils &amp;amp; stock/water, heat to boil &amp;amp; simmer until lentils cooked, adding more stock/water as necessary &amp;amp; stirring to keep from sticking &amp;amp; burning in the bottom of the pot.</description></item><item><title>Stacked - Buttermilk Berry Flapjacks</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-36-stacked/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-36-stacked/</guid><description>Nothing fancy, just a stack of buttermilk pancakes.</description></item><item><title>Stir Fry - Crispy Tofu + Sweet &amp; Sour Chicken</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-18-stir-fry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-18-stir-fry/</guid><description>Crispy Tofu &amp;amp; Vegetable Stir Fry Recipe: http://www.seriouseats.com/2014/02/vegan-experience-crispy-tofu-worth-eating-recipe.html Added a mix of other vegetables along with broccoli - snow peas, carrot, red &amp;amp; green bell pepper, asparagus, onion.</description></item><item><title>Tailgating - Chili Dog</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-37-tailgating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-37-tailgating/</guid><description>Standard Chili Dog topped with shredded monterey, onion, pickled wax peppers, and a dollop of sour cream on the side.</description></item><item><title>Tea - Green Tea Smoked Chicken Wings</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-19-tea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-19-tea/</guid><description>I used this recipe: http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2010/07/tea-smoked-chicken-wings.html Didn&amp;rsquo;t have any scallions handy, so I used cilantro for garnish instead. I was surprised at how strongly the smoked tea flavor came through even with the sauce. They were really good with a really unique flavor, but for the hassle of all of the smoke in the kitchen, I doubt I&amp;rsquo;d do this again outside of a special occasion.
I have one of those awful under oven broiler drawers and did around 5 minutes on each side to finish before tossing in the remaining sauce.</description></item><item><title>Tex-Mex - Enchiladas Combination Platter</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-5-tex-mex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-5-tex-mex/</guid><description>(Un)Finished plate first. Your standard enchiladas combination platter.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made the rice and beans several times before and they&amp;rsquo;re just the way I like them. This was my first time with this particular enchilada recipe. I really liked it overall, but would make some small tweaks next time.
The base sauce is pretty similar to how I usually do it, though i don&amp;rsquo;t typically add the roux and tend to keep it vegetarian without adding the beef.</description></item><item><title>Thai - Chicken Satay &amp; Dipping Sauce</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-22-thai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-22-thai/</guid><description>Almost turned into a complete failure when one leg of my preheated Weber charcoal grill collapsed and the whole thing overturned in the yard. Managed to recover part of the coals &amp;amp; get to cooking. Recipes: http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2016/08/thai-style-chicken-satay-peanut-coconut-tamarind-recipe.html http://www.seriouseats.com/2016/03/easy-vegan-crispy-tofu-spring-rolls-tamarind-peanut-dipping-sauce.html</description></item><item><title>Used to Dislike - Asparagus &amp; Brussel Sprouts</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-8-used-to-dislike/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2020/week-8-used-to-dislike/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s combine two vegetables every kid hates with something every kid loves - pizza! Asparagus pie goes first.
Shaved asparagus, shallots, white sauce, mozzarella, grated parmesan, garlic herb crust. This is one of two - the second also had crumbled bacon. The white sauce recipe comes from https://www.bonappetit.com/recipe/white-pizza-sauce .
Next, we have brussel sprouts, homemade chorizo, shallots, white sauce, mozzarella, grated parmesan. Some obvious execution errors here. Based on this recipe: https://www.</description></item><item><title>Vacation Food - Street Tacos</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-16-vacation-food/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-16-vacation-food/</guid><description>An attempt at recreating street tacos in Mexico.
Al pastor from SE - http://www.seriouseats.com/recipes/2013/05/tacos-al-pastor-recipe.html Quick pickled jalapeno, radish &amp;amp; carrot. Homemade tortilla - just masa &amp;amp; water.</description></item><item><title>Vanilla - Vanilla Blueberry Sticky Buns</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-28-vanilla/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2017/week-28-vanilla/</guid><description>Straight out of the oven. Maybe could have let them bake a few more minutes, but I was impatient. These are messy and delicious (they&amp;rsquo;re practically pure sugar, how could they not be?) The &amp;ldquo;goo&amp;rdquo; turns into caramel. Ran out of brown sugar, so substituted turbinado instead and used only unsalted butter.Recipe - https://www.halfbakedharvest.com/vanilla-bean-blueberry-lemon-cream-cheese-swirl-sticky-buns/</description></item><item><title>vertical3D</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/projects/vertical3d/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/projects/vertical3d/</guid><description>The Vertical3D project is a collection of C++ application libaries used across my various 3D application projects. There are libraries for image reading &amp;amp; writing (PNG, TGA, BMP, JPEG), font rendering (bmfont, FreeType), OpenAL audio, basic 3D data types, an event framework, OpenGL rendering helpers, and backend window drivers for SDL, SDL2, FLTK, and SMFL.
Voxel Voxel is a small application created for the purposes of testing out voxel-based random world generation and manipulation a la Minecraft.</description></item><item><title>Where You're From - Springfield-Style Cashew Chicken</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2019/week-51-where-youre-from/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/food/52-weeks-of-cooking/2019/week-51-where-youre-from/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>