<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Equipment on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/categories/equipment/</link><description>Recent content in Equipment on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 06:16:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/categories/equipment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Condenser-Boss Steam Condenser</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2020/02/21/condenser-boss/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 06:16:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2020/02/21/condenser-boss/</guid><description>This is the steam condenser from Brew-Boss available here: https://www.brew-boss.com/Condenser-Boss-Boil-Kettle-Condenser-p/cb-bb-apmount.htm This is the basic 1 . 5&amp;quot; tri-clamp mount configuration without any other bells and whistles.
Shipping was fast and the box was a bit beat up when I got it. It probably could have been packaged a little better, but it&amp;rsquo;s a big chunk of steel - it&amp;rsquo;d take quite a beating to do any damage to it.
Parts disassembled.</description></item><item><title>Backyard Brewery v2.0</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2016/07/23/backyard-brewery-v2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2016 06:16:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2016/07/23/backyard-brewery-v2/</guid><description>This is a portion of my old propane-fired homebrewing setup for 5 gallon batches.
The Gear (above) 10 gallon cooler MLT 30 plate Duda Diesel plate chiller 7 gallon BK Propane burner
BK Bayou Classic kettle w/ lid &amp;amp; burner w/ high pressure regulator. Kettle is fitted with ball valves for transferring &amp;amp; recirculating plus a sight glass &amp;amp; thermometer.
Lower Kettle All fittings are weldless. The valves are fitted with quick connect fittings.</description></item><item><title>Thermometers</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/thermometers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 06:16:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/thermometers/</guid><description>One of the most common useful pieces of equipment in the home brewery is the thermometer. Measuring, monitoring and ultimately, controlling temperature is a key aspect of producing quality beer. It starts with making sure that the water is being heated to the correct temperature for mashing and later on for sparging. It continues with getting the boiled wort cooled down to an appropriate temperature to pitch the yeast. After fermentation and carbonation, the beer needs to be cooled down to the correct serving temperature.</description></item></channel></rss>