<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Photography on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/categories/photography/</link><description>Recent content in Photography on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/categories/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Battle Royale – Flickr vs. Smugmug</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/12/22/battle-royale-flickr-vs-smugmug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/12/22/battle-royale-flickr-vs-smugmug/</guid><description>I spent a year with a pro Smugmug subscription. When it came time for renewal, I decided to make the switch
over to Flickr. In my year with Smugmug I had uploaded somewhere around 1500 photos. It would be no easy task to
migrate this number of images between services while maintaining their organization and associated metadata. So why do it and is it really worth it?
The target audience of Smugmug seems to be professional photographers.</description></item><item><title>Black/White</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/07/06/blackwhite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/07/06/blackwhite/</guid><description>The end of June marks the end of the first half of a year in pictures. It also signifies the end of a month-long experiment in black &amp;amp; white photography for my 365 project. I’ve never really appreciated working in the B&amp;amp;W format. If anything, I prefer to treat my images with a dialed down vibrance setting (a control available in Adobe Lightroom which applies a much smarter algorithmic approach to desaturation) in order to mute colors without removing them completely.</description></item><item><title>Pano</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/22/pano/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/22/pano/</guid><description>Less than a mile’s walk from my front door are the Buena Vista and Corona Heights parks. Albeit, a mile of steep hill climbing, the views of the city from the top are well worth it. I’ve recently created a few panoramas from photos taken at these locations. Hopefully they give a sense of the expansive city scenery below. Each image is linked to the full resolution version.
This image was merged from two shots taken from a street corner on Buena Vista East.</description></item><item><title>Inanimate February</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/05/inanimate-february/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/05/inanimate-february/</guid><description>Another month into the year means that many more days of 365 pictures. February was filled with rainy days. It’s a fact that can be evidenced by the large number of shots of (mostly) inanimate household objects. The limited opportunities for shooting excursions often challenged me to find interesting material in my local environment.
There was also ample occasion for pushing my post processing knowledge as well as continuing to develop my skills behind the lens.</description></item><item><title>Pillow Talk</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/19/pillow-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/19/pillow-talk/</guid><description>Almost everyone has hated Valentine’s Day at one time or another in their life. It’s most likely out of these deep feelings of love scorned masked by a disdain for corporate holidays that the great Pillow Fight was borne. This year marked the fourth anniversary of the San Francisco Pillow Fight. The rules were simple. You should bring a pillow to the Justin Herman Plaza at the Embarcadero in San Francisco on Valentine’s Day.</description></item><item><title>Year of the Ox</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/16/year-of-the-ox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/16/year-of-the-ox/</guid><description>The Chinese New Year Parade was started sometime in the 1860’s and remains one of the few night illuminated parades in the country. By now it carries strong corporate sponsorship, falling under the direction of the Chinese Chamber of Commerce – currently sponsored by Southwest Airlines.
The highlight of the parade is the 200 foot Golden Dragon also known as Gum Lung. It takes a team of over 100 to operate this illuminated monster as it winds its way along the parade route.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Pictures</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/31/everyday-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/31/everyday-pictures/</guid><description>2009 marks the beginning of my first full year of serious dSLR photography. I picked up my first dSLR camera kit – the Canon Digital Rebel XTi – in April of 2008. Since then I’ve already acquired various new lenses and other essential photo gear. Most recently I upgraded to the Canon 5D Mark II camera body. With a shooting capacity of around 400 RAW images on a 4GB card, the XTi was a great place to start with learning the photography basics.</description></item><item><title>And You Smell Like One Too</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/23/and-you-smell-like-one-too/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/23/and-you-smell-like-one-too/</guid><description>Continuing the field testing of my new Mark II, I decided to check off another item on my list of must visit locations and headed to the San Francisco Zoo. Getting there is a fairly trivial task – a simple matter of hopping on an outbound Muni L Taraval LRV and taking it all the way to the end. The line ends near the Great Highway which runs parallel to Ocean Beach right next to the zoo.</description></item><item><title>Shh, It’s a Secret</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/18/shh-its-a-secret/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/18/shh-its-a-secret/</guid><description>I recently read about a place known as the “secret sidewalk” located somewhere in the Niles Canyon area of the East Bay. Also in the area adjacent to this sidewalk were said to be the ruins of an old brick factory. Having recently acquired my upgraded camera body, this seemed a perfect location to break it in.
With unseasonably warm weather for mid-January reaching the mid 60’s, we set out on Saturday morning.</description></item></channel></rss>