<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/categories/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Concert Roundup</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/concert-roundup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/concert-roundup/</guid><description>The greatest shows are often put on by those bands that most of your friends have never heard of playing in small dives. Jason Webley started busking on the streets of Seattle with his distinctive brand of accordion music. He now tours venues around the world on his own and as part of his Monsters of Accordion tour, which showcases a number of other talented accordion musicians. He recently headlined a show with Sxip Shirey of the gypsy-folk-punk band Luminescent Orchestrii at the Bottom of the Hill in San Francisco.</description></item><item><title>The Big Damn Lie</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/28/the-big-damn-lie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/28/the-big-damn-lie/</guid><description>Vermillion Lies with Reverend Peyton’s Big Damn Band The Great American Music Hall Thursday, January 22nd, 2009
Established in 1907, The Great American Music Hall is San Francisco’s oldest nightclub. It is located on O’Farrell Street in the Tenderloin district. Getting to the venue is a simple matter – just take any Market Street bus to Van Ness and then any Van Ness bus to O’Farrell Street. It is a short walk further and just down the street from the also famous Mitchell Brothers O’Farrell Theatre.</description></item></channel></rss>