<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brewing Process on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/categories/brewing-process/</link><description>Recent content in Brewing Process on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 20:10:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/categories/brewing-process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick Tips for Optimizing Your Brew Day</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/quick-tips-for-optimizing-your-brew-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 20:10:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/quick-tips-for-optimizing-your-brew-day/</guid><description>The average all grain brew day generally takes between 4 and 6 hours from beginning to end. Some of the steps have a fixed duration. A 60 minute boil will never take any less time than an hour to complete. There’s no way around that fact. However, there are other areas with the potential to optimize and speed up the brew day.
When you optimize your own brew day look for ways not only to shorten the overall time spent brewing, but also to extract the most value from that time.</description></item><item><title>Keeping it Clean</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/keeping-it-clean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 22:12:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/keeping-it-clean/</guid><description>Cleaning &amp;amp; sanitization Most of the time involved in beer making is a hands off process as the yeast does its work. A comparatively small portion of time is actively spent on preparing the yeast, wort and, later on, packaging the resulting beer. A good deal of any brewer’s hands on time is dedicated to cleaning and sanitizing tasks. So what is the difference between the two processes and when is each appropriate?</description></item><item><title>10 Essential Brew Day Terms Defined</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/10-essential-brew-day-terms-defined/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/10-essential-brew-day-terms-defined/</guid><description>Newcomers to the homebrewing world will quickly encounter a vast landscape of unfamiliar acronyms and bizarre terminology. When you’re still trying to learn the basic brewing processes, finding your way through the slew of unusual jargon adds its own steep learning curve. Here are a few of the most common terms along with their definitions to help ease the way.
LHBS – Local Home Brew Store The LHBS is the place where your brew days will often begin.</description></item><item><title>Five Tips For a Successful Brew Day</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/five-tips-for-a-successful-brew-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 06:22:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/five-tips-for-a-successful-brew-day/</guid><description>1 – Hot Break Achieving a good rolling boil is an important step in the beer making process for several reasons. First, boiling sterilizes the beer, killing any unwanted bacteria that might be hanging around just waiting to spoil your hard work. Boil off reduces the overall volume, concentrating it. Without boiling, you’d end up with a beer that probably tasted water down. Boiling also causes caramelization, contributing additional flavor to the beer.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Extract Brewing Methods</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/beyond-extract-brewing-methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 23:53:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/beyond-extract-brewing-methods/</guid><description>There is no question that award winning beers can be made using malt extract as the the basis of their recipe. However, when using extracts, much of the work in converting the grain’s starches into usable sugars has already been done for the brewer. This also means that much of the control over the end product is in the hands of the extract producers and not the brewer. By using all grain and leaving malt extracts behind, brewers can take more control over the flavor profiles of the beers they are creating.</description></item><item><title>Extract Brewing Methods</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/extract-brewing-methods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 01:23:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/extract-brewing-methods/</guid><description>There may be almost as many ways to make beer as there are different styles of beer. While the basic formula is to combine a hoppy sugary liquid with yeast to ultimately produce a fermented beverage, the steps to get there can vary greatly. These different approaches also tend to affect brewing process, equipment and the ingredients that are required.
Hopped Kits At the simplest end of the spectrum are pre-hopped extract kits.</description></item></channel></rss>