<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Brews on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/categories/brews/</link><description>Recent content in Brews on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/categories/brews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Full Steam Ahead</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/19/full-steam-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/19/full-steam-ahead/</guid><description>I made my first steam beer about six months ago. It was my first brew of the year (not counting mead) and my first attempt at coming up with my own recipe. While there were a number of milestones that came with that brew, I wasn’t all that thrilled with the resulting beer. It wasn’t bad, but try as I might, I just could never find anything particularly noteworthy about it.</description></item><item><title>The Mayan</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/15/the-mayan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/15/the-mayan/</guid><description>The brewing process for me often starts with a simple concept or core thematic element. It could be an ingredient, a style, or some other idea serving as the inspiration for the beer. In this case a recent thread in the HBT forums brought up the idea of an end of the world brew.
According to some interpretations of the Mayan calendar the world is set to end on December, 23rd 2012.</description></item><item><title>The Belgian</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/07/31/the-belgian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/07/31/the-belgian/</guid><description>It’s been over a year since I’ve brewed something falling into the Belgian style category.
My last attempt was a golden strong ale called Blonde Bombshell.
It was also my second brewing experience ever. In the intervening time my knowledge and process has changed significantly.
I’ve gone from brewing partial-boil extract recipes taken from the internet to all-grain full-boil batches created from my own custom designed recipes. Regardless my advances, I’m always finding areas of my techniques and processes to improve upon from one session to the next.</description></item><item><title>Cherry Wheat</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/20/cherry-wheat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/20/cherry-wheat/</guid><description>As I’ve slowly worked my way through various new styles and ingredients to experiment with, fruit has long been on my list. I’ve been looking forward to making a beer featuring cherries for nearly a year now. The idea first came to me after seeing fresh ripe cherries at a local farmers market one weekend. Unfortunately, it was already late in the season and by the time I was finally ready the opportunity for market fresh cherries had passed.</description></item><item><title>Shilling Parti-gyle</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/17/shilling-parti-gyle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/17/shilling-parti-gyle/</guid><description>Batch #12 – All Grain #7
One of my favorite batches to date has been my Strong Scotch Ale all-grain recipe. One of the signature characteristics of most Scottish ales is a deep, rich malt profile. The flavors often a result of early century procedures producing kettle-scortched wort, modern day recreations are created from the caramelized reduction of the first runnings which is added back in with the rest of the wort at the end of the boil.</description></item><item><title>The Commoner</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/12/the-commoner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/12/the-commoner/</guid><description>Batch #11 – All Grain #6
I’m kicking off the 2011 brewing season with what I had anticipated on being my last brew of 2010. I was hoping to get this brew in before the end of the year. Unfortunately, an order shipment delay from MoreBeer followed by a month long chest cold and a grain mill debacle added up to a two month brewing hiatus.
Instead of my usual internet recipe search, I’ve decided to take another big step and develop my own recipe.</description></item><item><title>Razzmatazz</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/07/razzmatazz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/07/razzmatazz/</guid><description>I’ve been wanting to branch out from beer and try my hand at brewing mead for quite a while. Other than the suggestion that a fermented alcoholic beverage made from honey and fruit sounds delicious, I really don’t know what I’m getting into. Given that I’m in completely unknown territory here, I really don’t want to commit to a full 5 gallon batch of something I might end up not liking.</description></item><item><title>Old School</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/24/old-school/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/24/old-school/</guid><description>Batch #9 – All Grain #5
It’s time for a new recipe and all new mistakes. This is batch #2 on my v3.0 brewing system – ninth overall since I started home brewing and the fifth all-grain. This time around I’m finally tackling something that I’ve been wanting to do for almost as long as I’ve been brewing. It’s what I’ve come to call the “Vertical Epic” named after a series of beers created by Stone Brewing Co.</description></item><item><title>Back Yard Shambling</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/14/back-yard-shambling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/14/back-yard-shambling/</guid><description>It’s been a few months since my last brew. Since then, I’ve moved into a new apartment (to be closer to my brewing assistant, of course). While I still have the kitchen space and stove capacity to do my brewing inside, I’ve decided to move my brewing out of the kitchen and into the back yard. This means yet another round of upgrades to my equipment – and one of the biggest investments in new gear to date.</description></item><item><title>Arrogance, Party of Two</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/01/arrogance-party-of-two/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/01/arrogance-party-of-two/</guid><description>Batch #7 – All Grain #3 Brewed: 8-9-10
Grain Bill 15# Pale 2 Row .5# Aromatic .5# Biscuit .5# Caramunich .5# Special B Hop Schedule 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 60 minutes 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 45 minutes 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 2 minutes 5/8oz Chinook 11% AA @ 2 weeks Yeast WLP001 Misc 3.5oz. American Oak Cubes @ 1 week Brew Stats Boil: 90 minutes Mash: 60 minutes Strike Temperature: 162° Mash Temperature:154° Sparge Temperature: 168° Vitals O.</description></item><item><title>El Jefe – American Hefeweizen</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/11/07/el-jefe-american-hefeweizen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/11/07/el-jefe-american-hefeweizen/</guid><description>Batch #6 – All Grain #2 (05-02-10)
The American Homebrewers Association celebrates National Homebrew Day with an event called Big Brew. It is held on the first Saturday of May each year. The idea is that you get a group together and everyone around the world who is participating brews at the same time. The AHA has a section of their site dedicated to tracking participants and the overall results of the event.</description></item><item><title>Scottish Zombie Jesus</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/09/22/scottish-zombie-jesus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/09/22/scottish-zombie-jesus/</guid><description>Batch #5 – All Grain #1.
Brewed: 04-04-10
This is my first all grain batch and my second to be kegged. I begin my recipe search as I most often do – by browsing the recipe database at HBT. Once again, I know I’m going to go with a recipe in a style I haven’t done before. This time I am picking the Scotch Ale style, a strong ale with a strong smoky malt profile.</description></item><item><title>Great Lakes Edmund Fitzgerald Porter Clone</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/04/22/great-lakes-edmund-fitzgerald-porter-clone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/04/22/great-lakes-edmund-fitzgerald-porter-clone/</guid><description>This is batch #3.
My goal with each new batch of beer is to do something I’ve never done before. I use this experimentation as a way explore and learn about the world of beer and brewing. There are usually several new things that I introduce each time I brew, but overall I try to limit the variables to a small extent in order to help me understand the role that each one plays.</description></item><item><title>Valentine’s Edition Brew Day – Bell’s Two Hearted Ale</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/02/19/valentines-edition-brew-day-bells-two-hearted-ale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/02/19/valentines-edition-brew-day-bells-two-hearted-ale/</guid><description>So, technically, the brew was on the day after Valentine’s Day (or as it is affectionately known around the house since it coincides with the Chinese New Year, Loony FatChoyintine’s Day). The ingredients were sourced on the most special of holidays, though.
Bell’s Two Hearted Ale is an IPA brewed by Bell’s out of Kalamazoo, Michigan. Unfortunately, it isn’t available on the west coast. My first introduction to it was through a visit to the Patton Alley Pub during my vacation back home in Springfield, Missouri.</description></item><item><title>The Belgian Blonde</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/12/22/the-belgian-blonde/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/12/22/the-belgian-blonde/</guid><description>This is my second batch of craft home brewed beer. When I set out to pick the recipe this time around I had several goals in mind. Based on my experiences the first time, I knew I wanted to expand on the knowledge and techniques I had used so far. It needed to be an even bigger beer. Instead of using dry yeast it had to be a liquid variety and use a proper starter.</description></item></channel></rss>