<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homebrews on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrew/</link><description>Recent content in Homebrews on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 17:40:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/homebrew/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vent Hood Build</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/09/vent-hood-build/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2015 17:40:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/09/vent-hood-build/</guid><description>When I originally built the electric brewery, it was located at the back of the garage in front of a window. During boils I would open the window and point a small fan from above the kettle to move steam outside. In our new house, the brewery got moved out of the garage and into its own space in the basement. This meant I would need a new ventilation system.</description></item><item><title>Holiday Poster Boards</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/07/holiday-poster-boards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 19:18:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2015/08/07/holiday-poster-boards/</guid><description>A while back [ok – headed toward 2 years ago now – I’m way behind on blog posts], Creative Market held a Christmas party, giving its employees and community members an opportunity to hang out and interact. As the Creative Market brewer-in-residence, I was asked to provide some beer for the event. This would be a general audience event and not a room full of seasoned homebrew beer geeks like I was more accustomed to.</description></item><item><title>Electric Brewery Upgrade – Part 1</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/2013/05/15/electric-brewery-upgrade-part-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/2013/05/15/electric-brewery-upgrade-part-1/</guid><description>It’s closing in on two years now since the last blog update. Even though I haven’t been keeping content updated, I’ve still been busy brewing. Maybe a future post will spend a bit more time reflecting on all of those brews. That is not this post. This post is all about the new pilot brewing system I built over the past winter.
Incremental Updates I’ve been brewing on essentially the same propane system for the past several years with just a few minor tweaks here and there.</description></item><item><title>Product Review: Taylor Digital Thermometer</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/product-review-taylor-digital-thermometer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 23:26:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/product-review-taylor-digital-thermometer/</guid><description>Pros Price: It can typically be found on sale online for $16-$20.
Temperature Alarm: This works great in the HLT to know when strike or sparge water has reached its target temperature. It can also be used in the boil kettle to notify you when the wort is approaching a boiling point and the most susceptible to boil overs.
Timer: Use this to keep track of when the mash and boil are done.</description></item><item><title>Quick Tips for Optimizing Your Brew Day</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/quick-tips-for-optimizing-your-brew-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 20:10:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/quick-tips-for-optimizing-your-brew-day/</guid><description>The average all grain brew day generally takes between 4 and 6 hours from beginning to end. Some of the steps have a fixed duration. A 60 minute boil will never take any less time than an hour to complete. There’s no way around that fact. However, there are other areas with the potential to optimize and speed up the brew day.
When you optimize your own brew day look for ways not only to shorten the overall time spent brewing, but also to extract the most value from that time.</description></item><item><title>Keeping it Clean</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/keeping-it-clean/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 22:12:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/keeping-it-clean/</guid><description>Cleaning &amp;amp; sanitization Most of the time involved in beer making is a hands off process as the yeast does its work. A comparatively small portion of time is actively spent on preparing the yeast, wort and, later on, packaging the resulting beer. A good deal of any brewer’s hands on time is dedicated to cleaning and sanitizing tasks. So what is the difference between the two processes and when is each appropriate?</description></item><item><title>10 Essential Brew Day Terms Defined</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/10-essential-brew-day-terms-defined/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/10-essential-brew-day-terms-defined/</guid><description>Newcomers to the homebrewing world will quickly encounter a vast landscape of unfamiliar acronyms and bizarre terminology. When you’re still trying to learn the basic brewing processes, finding your way through the slew of unusual jargon adds its own steep learning curve. Here are a few of the most common terms along with their definitions to help ease the way.
LHBS – Local Home Brew Store The LHBS is the place where your brew days will often begin.</description></item><item><title>Five Tips For a Successful Brew Day</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/five-tips-for-a-successful-brew-day/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 06:22:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/five-tips-for-a-successful-brew-day/</guid><description>1 – Hot Break Achieving a good rolling boil is an important step in the beer making process for several reasons. First, boiling sterilizes the beer, killing any unwanted bacteria that might be hanging around just waiting to spoil your hard work. Boil off reduces the overall volume, concentrating it. Without boiling, you’d end up with a beer that probably tasted water down. Boiling also causes caramelization, contributing additional flavor to the beer.</description></item><item><title>Beyond Extract Brewing Methods</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/beyond-extract-brewing-methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2012 23:53:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/beyond-extract-brewing-methods/</guid><description>There is no question that award winning beers can be made using malt extract as the the basis of their recipe. However, when using extracts, much of the work in converting the grain’s starches into usable sugars has already been done for the brewer. This also means that much of the control over the end product is in the hands of the extract producers and not the brewer. By using all grain and leaving malt extracts behind, brewers can take more control over the flavor profiles of the beers they are creating.</description></item><item><title>Extract Brewing Methods</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/extract-brewing-methods/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 01:23:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/extract-brewing-methods/</guid><description>There may be almost as many ways to make beer as there are different styles of beer. While the basic formula is to combine a hoppy sugary liquid with yeast to ultimately produce a fermented beverage, the steps to get there can vary greatly. These different approaches also tend to affect brewing process, equipment and the ingredients that are required.
Hopped Kits At the simplest end of the spectrum are pre-hopped extract kits.</description></item><item><title>Thermometers</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/thermometers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2012 06:16:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/thermometers/</guid><description>One of the most common useful pieces of equipment in the home brewery is the thermometer. Measuring, monitoring and ultimately, controlling temperature is a key aspect of producing quality beer. It starts with making sure that the water is being heated to the correct temperature for mashing and later on for sparging. It continues with getting the boiled wort cooled down to an appropriate temperature to pitch the yeast. After fermentation and carbonation, the beer needs to be cooled down to the correct serving temperature.</description></item><item><title>A Beer Style Primer</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/introduction-styles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2012 06:40:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/introduction-styles/</guid><description>Beers are typically categorized by their style. Styles are primarily defined by characteristics such as color, bitterness, alcohol content, ingredients, aroma, body, mouthfeel and flavor. They also often carry particular historical and regional significance. For instance, the Berliner Weisse began as a regional specialty style of Berlin while Munich Helles was first created in Munich.
While beers have probably been categorized into different styles based on their differing properties for as long as they have been brewed, it is possibly the acclaimed English beer writer Michael Jackson who pioneered modern beer style definitions with his 1977 book “The World Guide To Beer”.</description></item><item><title>Full Steam Ahead</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/19/full-steam-ahead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/19/full-steam-ahead/</guid><description>I made my first steam beer about six months ago. It was my first brew of the year (not counting mead) and my first attempt at coming up with my own recipe. While there were a number of milestones that came with that brew, I wasn’t all that thrilled with the resulting beer. It wasn’t bad, but try as I might, I just could never find anything particularly noteworthy about it.</description></item><item><title>The Mayan</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/15/the-mayan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/08/15/the-mayan/</guid><description>The brewing process for me often starts with a simple concept or core thematic element. It could be an ingredient, a style, or some other idea serving as the inspiration for the beer. In this case a recent thread in the HBT forums brought up the idea of an end of the world brew.
According to some interpretations of the Mayan calendar the world is set to end on December, 23rd 2012.</description></item><item><title>The Belgian</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/07/31/the-belgian/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/07/31/the-belgian/</guid><description>It’s been over a year since I’ve brewed something falling into the Belgian style category.
My last attempt was a golden strong ale called Blonde Bombshell.
It was also my second brewing experience ever. In the intervening time my knowledge and process has changed significantly.
I’ve gone from brewing partial-boil extract recipes taken from the internet to all-grain full-boil batches created from my own custom designed recipes. Regardless my advances, I’m always finding areas of my techniques and processes to improve upon from one session to the next.</description></item><item><title>Cherry Wheat</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/20/cherry-wheat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/20/cherry-wheat/</guid><description>As I’ve slowly worked my way through various new styles and ingredients to experiment with, fruit has long been on my list. I’ve been looking forward to making a beer featuring cherries for nearly a year now. The idea first came to me after seeing fresh ripe cherries at a local farmers market one weekend. Unfortunately, it was already late in the season and by the time I was finally ready the opportunity for market fresh cherries had passed.</description></item><item><title>Shilling Parti-gyle</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/17/shilling-parti-gyle/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/05/17/shilling-parti-gyle/</guid><description>Batch #12 – All Grain #7
One of my favorite batches to date has been my Strong Scotch Ale all-grain recipe. One of the signature characteristics of most Scottish ales is a deep, rich malt profile. The flavors often a result of early century procedures producing kettle-scortched wort, modern day recreations are created from the caramelized reduction of the first runnings which is added back in with the rest of the wort at the end of the boil.</description></item><item><title>The Commoner</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/12/the-commoner/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/12/the-commoner/</guid><description>Batch #11 – All Grain #6
I’m kicking off the 2011 brewing season with what I had anticipated on being my last brew of 2010. I was hoping to get this brew in before the end of the year. Unfortunately, an order shipment delay from MoreBeer followed by a month long chest cold and a grain mill debacle added up to a two month brewing hiatus.
Instead of my usual internet recipe search, I’ve decided to take another big step and develop my own recipe.</description></item><item><title>Razzmatazz</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/07/razzmatazz/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/02/07/razzmatazz/</guid><description>I’ve been wanting to branch out from beer and try my hand at brewing mead for quite a while. Other than the suggestion that a fermented alcoholic beverage made from honey and fruit sounds delicious, I really don’t know what I’m getting into. Given that I’m in completely unknown territory here, I really don’t want to commit to a full 5 gallon batch of something I might end up not liking.</description></item><item><title>Old School</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/24/old-school/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/24/old-school/</guid><description>Batch #9 – All Grain #5
It’s time for a new recipe and all new mistakes. This is batch #2 on my v3.0 brewing system – ninth overall since I started home brewing and the fifth all-grain. This time around I’m finally tackling something that I’ve been wanting to do for almost as long as I’ve been brewing. It’s what I’ve come to call the “Vertical Epic” named after a series of beers created by Stone Brewing Co.</description></item><item><title>Back Yard Shambling</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/14/back-yard-shambling/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/14/back-yard-shambling/</guid><description>It’s been a few months since my last brew. Since then, I’ve moved into a new apartment (to be closer to my brewing assistant, of course). While I still have the kitchen space and stove capacity to do my brewing inside, I’ve decided to move my brewing out of the kitchen and into the back yard. This means yet another round of upgrades to my equipment – and one of the biggest investments in new gear to date.</description></item><item><title>Arrogance, Party of Two</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/01/arrogance-party-of-two/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2011/01/01/arrogance-party-of-two/</guid><description>Batch #7 – All Grain #3 Brewed: 8-9-10
Grain Bill 15# Pale 2 Row .5# Aromatic .5# Biscuit .5# Caramunich .5# Special B Hop Schedule 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 60 minutes 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 45 minutes 1oz Chinook 11% AA @ 2 minutes 5/8oz Chinook 11% AA @ 2 weeks Yeast WLP001 Misc 3.5oz. American Oak Cubes @ 1 week Brew Stats Boil: 90 minutes Mash: 60 minutes Strike Temperature: 162° Mash Temperature:154° Sparge Temperature: 168° Vitals O.</description></item><item><title>El Jefe – American Hefeweizen</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/11/07/el-jefe-american-hefeweizen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/11/07/el-jefe-american-hefeweizen/</guid><description>Batch #6 – All Grain #2 (05-02-10)
The American Homebrewers Association celebrates National Homebrew Day with an event called Big Brew. It is held on the first Saturday of May each year. The idea is that you get a group together and everyone around the world who is participating brews at the same time. The AHA has a section of their site dedicated to tracking participants and the overall results of the event.</description></item><item><title>Scottish Zombie Jesus</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/09/22/scottish-zombie-jesus/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/09/22/scottish-zombie-jesus/</guid><description>Batch #5 – All Grain #1.
Brewed: 04-04-10
This is my first all grain batch and my second to be kegged. I begin my recipe search as I most often do – by browsing the recipe database at HBT. Once again, I know I’m going to go with a recipe in a style I haven’t done before. This time I am picking the Scotch Ale style, a strong ale with a strong smoky malt profile.</description></item><item><title>Great Lakes Edmund Fitzgerald Porter Clone</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/04/22/great-lakes-edmund-fitzgerald-porter-clone/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/04/22/great-lakes-edmund-fitzgerald-porter-clone/</guid><description>This is batch #3.
My goal with each new batch of beer is to do something I’ve never done before. I use this experimentation as a way explore and learn about the world of beer and brewing. There are usually several new things that I introduce each time I brew, but overall I try to limit the variables to a small extent in order to help me understand the role that each one plays.</description></item><item><title>Valentine’s Edition Brew Day – Bell’s Two Hearted Ale</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/02/19/valentines-edition-brew-day-bells-two-hearted-ale/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2010/02/19/valentines-edition-brew-day-bells-two-hearted-ale/</guid><description>So, technically, the brew was on the day after Valentine’s Day (or as it is affectionately known around the house since it coincides with the Chinese New Year, Loony FatChoyintine’s Day). The ingredients were sourced on the most special of holidays, though.
Bell’s Two Hearted Ale is an IPA brewed by Bell’s out of Kalamazoo, Michigan. Unfortunately, it isn’t available on the west coast. My first introduction to it was through a visit to the Patton Alley Pub during my vacation back home in Springfield, Missouri.</description></item><item><title>The Belgian Blonde</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/12/22/the-belgian-blonde/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/12/22/the-belgian-blonde/</guid><description>This is my second batch of craft home brewed beer. When I set out to pick the recipe this time around I had several goals in mind. Based on my experiences the first time, I knew I wanted to expand on the knowledge and techniques I had used so far. It needed to be an even bigger beer. Instead of using dry yeast it had to be a liquid variety and use a proper starter.</description></item><item><title>Brewcraft</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/06/14/brewcraft/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/homebrewing/2009/06/14/brewcraft/</guid><description>My homebrew adventure began with a trip to the local supply shop, San Francisco Brewcraft.
After a few weeks of internet research I had a pretty good idea of what I needed to get started. Most of the necessary equipment is typically
packaged up into custom kits sold by just about every brewing store around. I settled on a mid-range kit composed of a 6.5 gallon plastic primary fermenting bucket (with spigot), 5 gallon glass carboy secondary fermenter, stoppers, airlocks, cleaning brushes, hose, funnel, bottle caps and capper, auto-siphon, hydrometer, and the ingredients for the first batch of beer.</description></item></channel></rss>