<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:17:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS CodeCommit</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2017/01/09/aws-codecommit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2017 00:17:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2017/01/09/aws-codecommit/</guid><description>The Picture So Far I’ve used a number of VCS flavors and platforms over the years. I started with CVS, moved on to SVN for a good long while, and was finally converted over to Git long after it had achieved its critical mass. I had a sourceforge account (which I loved) long before it became the reviled product it is today, flirted for a bit with beanstalk, and now use github in its public and private forms on a daily basis.</description></item><item><title>Pressing Matters</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2015/08/10/pressing-matters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 06:50:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2015/08/10/pressing-matters/</guid><description>WordPress to Octopress and Back Again This site is once again running on WordPress. It’s been through many changes since its earliest incarnation as handwritten static HTML. There have been versions based on custom PHP frameworks, a pyblosxom-based variant, and most recently, the Octopress installation. Directly prior to Octopress, the site had already been using WordPress. So why did I leave and why did I come back?
What I don’t like about WordPress Its relative ease of installation and use for newcomers belies the big cumbersome application that WordPress really is underneath.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Fermentation Controller – Part 3</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/05/14/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/05/14/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-3/</guid><description>Part 1 and part 2 covered getting the Raspberry Pi booted up and configured with a basic software stack for developing on top of. With that out of the way, we can focus on wiring up the remaining hardware components. There will be two types of IO devices wired to the Pi – temperature sensors and SSR’s.
Temperature Sensors The temperature sensors being used are small digital thermometers which communicate using the Dallas 1-wire network protocol.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Fermentation Controller – Part 2</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/24/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/24/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-2/</guid><description>In part 1 I walked through getting the Raspberry Pi initially up and running. Once you’re logged in, you can immediately start hooking up sensors and start polling them directly from the command line. However, you’re likely going to want some more software installed for additional tasks. For my fermentation controller, I’ve decided on the following software stack.
Software Stack Graphite StatsD Node.js MongoDB All of the data read from sensors along with GPIO state changes will all be recorded in Graphite.</description></item><item><title>Raspberry Pi Fermentation Controller – Part 1</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/20/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2013/04/20/raspberry-pi-fermentation-controller-part-1/</guid><description>The Raspberry Pi is a cheap single-board computer with generic IO features which make it ideal for brewery automation projects. The BrewPi project is just one example. I decided to assemble a similar project with the goal of being able to monitor, log, and control the fermentation temperature of two 5-6 gallon carboys of fermenting beer.
Parts List Raspberry Pi SD Card WiFi Adapter SD Card Reader Micro USB Power Adapter Network cable Bootstrapping The Raspberry Pi board by itself isn’t actually enough to do anything with.</description></item><item><title>Monterey Getaway</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2011/02/24/monterey-getaway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2011/02/24/monterey-getaway/</guid><description>While recently assembling the brew log page, I realized that I haven’t written about anything other than brewing beer in quite a while. When I initially started writing I had four primary concepts in mind – a blend of food, beer, travel, and photography. Over time it seems some of these have fallen by the wayside in favor of my brewing posts. So, this post is a bit of catch up for the non-brewing category.</description></item><item><title>Pretty Good Year</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/06/20/pretty-good-year/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/06/20/pretty-good-year/</guid><description>My last vacation back to Missouri was for Thanksgiving last year. Here is a short video composed of snippets of footage I shot while spending time with the family. Everything was shot with a Canon 5D Mark II outfitted with a Canon EF 24-70mm f/2.8L USM Lens and then edited together with Final Cut Pro on a MacBook Pro.
Thanksgiving 2009 from Josh Farr on Vimeo.
Also – the Flickr Set from the trip.</description></item><item><title>Game Time Grub – Hot Wings</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/02/07/game-time-grub-hot-wings/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2010/02/07/game-time-grub-hot-wings/</guid><description>These are hands down, the best wings I’ve ever made. Never mind that the recipe was hastily hacked together from multiple online recipe sources and only used as a rough guideline once in the kitchen. And don’t even think of bringing up the fact that I’m basing this on a sample size of one and have never actually made hot wings before. Caveats in mind, here it is.
Sauce
1 cup Greek yogurt 1/4 cup crumbled Bleu cheese 2 tbsp finely grated red onion Wings</description></item><item><title>Battle Royale – Flickr vs. Smugmug</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/12/22/battle-royale-flickr-vs-smugmug/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/12/22/battle-royale-flickr-vs-smugmug/</guid><description>I spent a year with a pro Smugmug subscription. When it came time for renewal, I decided to make the switch
over to Flickr. In my year with Smugmug I had uploaded somewhere around 1500 photos. It would be no easy task to
migrate this number of images between services while maintaining their organization and associated metadata. So why do it and is it really worth it?
The target audience of Smugmug seems to be professional photographers.</description></item><item><title>Black/White</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/07/06/blackwhite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/07/06/blackwhite/</guid><description>The end of June marks the end of the first half of a year in pictures. It also signifies the end of a month-long experiment in black &amp;amp; white photography for my 365 project. I’ve never really appreciated working in the B&amp;amp;W format. If anything, I prefer to treat my images with a dialed down vibrance setting (a control available in Adobe Lightroom which applies a much smarter algorithmic approach to desaturation) in order to mute colors without removing them completely.</description></item><item><title>The Mother Road</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/06/01/the-mother-road/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/06/01/the-mother-road/</guid><description>At the end of April, I took a bit of vacation time and spent five days driving from San Francisco, CA to my hometown of Springfield, MO. While large portions of the journey were spent mindlessly blazing down the interstate on autopilot, some sections were devoted to sightseeing along the historic Route 66. The 2300 mile adventure was a trip back through eras long past.
Oatman, Arizona (population ~128) represents an early 20th century gold mining town turned tourist destination nestled in the Black Mountains.</description></item><item><title>Concert Roundup</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/concert-roundup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/concert-roundup/</guid><description>The greatest shows are often put on by those bands that most of your friends have never heard of playing in small dives. Jason Webley started busking on the streets of Seattle with his distinctive brand of accordion music. He now tours venues around the world on his own and as part of his Monsters of Accordion tour, which showcases a number of other talented accordion musicians. He recently headlined a show with Sxip Shirey of the gypsy-folk-punk band Luminescent Orchestrii at the Bottom of the Hill in San Francisco.</description></item><item><title>Mexico</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/mexico/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/mexico/</guid><description>As I’m preparing to embark on a new road trip to the Midwest, I’m reflecting on other past trips. This post has been sitting as a draft for a few months now. It’s about time it finally got polished up and published.
I kept a short journal of the first few days of my vacation in Mexico near the small fishing village of Teacapan. This is how it starts…
It was a 4AM wake up call and I had a 6AM flight from SFO to Phoenix.</description></item><item><title>Pano</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/22/pano/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/22/pano/</guid><description>Less than a mile’s walk from my front door are the Buena Vista and Corona Heights parks. Albeit, a mile of steep hill climbing, the views of the city from the top are well worth it. I’ve recently created a few panoramas from photos taken at these locations. Hopefully they give a sense of the expansive city scenery below. Each image is linked to the full resolution version.
This image was merged from two shots taken from a street corner on Buena Vista East.</description></item><item><title>Inanimate February</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/05/inanimate-february/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/03/05/inanimate-february/</guid><description>Another month into the year means that many more days of 365 pictures. February was filled with rainy days. It’s a fact that can be evidenced by the large number of shots of (mostly) inanimate household objects. The limited opportunities for shooting excursions often challenged me to find interesting material in my local environment.
There was also ample occasion for pushing my post processing knowledge as well as continuing to develop my skills behind the lens.</description></item><item><title>Pillow Talk</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/19/pillow-talk/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/19/pillow-talk/</guid><description>Almost everyone has hated Valentine’s Day at one time or another in their life. It’s most likely out of these deep feelings of love scorned masked by a disdain for corporate holidays that the great Pillow Fight was borne. This year marked the fourth anniversary of the San Francisco Pillow Fight. The rules were simple. You should bring a pillow to the Justin Herman Plaza at the Embarcadero in San Francisco on Valentine’s Day.</description></item><item><title>Year of the Ox</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/16/year-of-the-ox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/02/16/year-of-the-ox/</guid><description>The Chinese New Year Parade was started sometime in the 1860’s and remains one of the few night illuminated parades in the country. By now it carries strong corporate sponsorship, falling under the direction of the Chinese Chamber of Commerce – currently sponsored by Southwest Airlines.
The highlight of the parade is the 200 foot Golden Dragon also known as Gum Lung. It takes a team of over 100 to operate this illuminated monster as it winds its way along the parade route.</description></item><item><title>Everyday Pictures</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/31/everyday-pictures/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/31/everyday-pictures/</guid><description>2009 marks the beginning of my first full year of serious dSLR photography. I picked up my first dSLR camera kit – the Canon Digital Rebel XTi – in April of 2008. Since then I’ve already acquired various new lenses and other essential photo gear. Most recently I upgraded to the Canon 5D Mark II camera body. With a shooting capacity of around 400 RAW images on a 4GB card, the XTi was a great place to start with learning the photography basics.</description></item><item><title>The Big Damn Lie</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/28/the-big-damn-lie/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/28/the-big-damn-lie/</guid><description>Vermillion Lies with Reverend Peyton’s Big Damn Band The Great American Music Hall Thursday, January 22nd, 2009
Established in 1907, The Great American Music Hall is San Francisco’s oldest nightclub. It is located on O’Farrell Street in the Tenderloin district. Getting to the venue is a simple matter – just take any Market Street bus to Van Ness and then any Van Ness bus to O’Farrell Street. It is a short walk further and just down the street from the also famous Mitchell Brothers O’Farrell Theatre.</description></item><item><title>And You Smell Like One Too</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/23/and-you-smell-like-one-too/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/23/and-you-smell-like-one-too/</guid><description>Continuing the field testing of my new Mark II, I decided to check off another item on my list of must visit locations and headed to the San Francisco Zoo. Getting there is a fairly trivial task – a simple matter of hopping on an outbound Muni L Taraval LRV and taking it all the way to the end. The line ends near the Great Highway which runs parallel to Ocean Beach right next to the zoo.</description></item><item><title>Shh, It’s a Secret</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/18/shh-its-a-secret/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/01/18/shh-its-a-secret/</guid><description>I recently read about a place known as the “secret sidewalk” located somewhere in the Niles Canyon area of the East Bay. Also in the area adjacent to this sidewalk were said to be the ruins of an old brick factory. Having recently acquired my upgraded camera body, this seemed a perfect location to break it in.
With unseasonably warm weather for mid-January reaching the mid 60’s, we set out on Saturday morning.</description></item></channel></rss>