<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel on farrcraft.com</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/categories/travel/</link><description>Recent content in Travel on farrcraft.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://farrcraft.com/categories/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Monterey Getaway</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2011/02/24/monterey-getaway/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2011/02/24/monterey-getaway/</guid><description>While recently assembling the brew log page, I realized that I haven’t written about anything other than brewing beer in quite a while. When I initially started writing I had four primary concepts in mind – a blend of food, beer, travel, and photography. Over time it seems some of these have fallen by the wayside in favor of my brewing posts. So, this post is a bit of catch up for the non-brewing category.</description></item><item><title>The Mother Road</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/06/01/the-mother-road/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/06/01/the-mother-road/</guid><description>At the end of April, I took a bit of vacation time and spent five days driving from San Francisco, CA to my hometown of Springfield, MO. While large portions of the journey were spent mindlessly blazing down the interstate on autopilot, some sections were devoted to sightseeing along the historic Route 66. The 2300 mile adventure was a trip back through eras long past.
Oatman, Arizona (population ~128) represents an early 20th century gold mining town turned tourist destination nestled in the Black Mountains.</description></item><item><title>Mexico</title><link>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/mexico/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://farrcraft.com/blog/2009/04/24/mexico/</guid><description>As I’m preparing to embark on a new road trip to the Midwest, I’m reflecting on other past trips. This post has been sitting as a draft for a few months now. It’s about time it finally got polished up and published.
I kept a short journal of the first few days of my vacation in Mexico near the small fishing village of Teacapan. This is how it starts…
It was a 4AM wake up call and I had a 6AM flight from SFO to Phoenix.</description></item></channel></rss>